<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<events>

    <event>
        <lang>ru</lang>
        <startDate>2018-12-01</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-12-01</endDate>
        <location>Samara, Russia</location>
        <speaker>Nikita Puzankov</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin Samara User Group</title>
        <subject>Kotlin for Hackathons</subject>
        <url>https://samara-it-community.timepad.ru/event/845193/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Kotlin is a good language in many aspects. This talk will tell you about the main features that make it the right choice in case of fast development or prototyping. The real example of a hackathon project in Kotlin and comparison with equivalent parts of code in Java.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>
    <event>
        <lang>ru</lang>
        <startDate>2018-12-01</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-12-01</endDate>
        <location>Samara, Russia</location>
        <speaker>Nikita Fedyunin</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin Samara User Group</title>
        <subject>Kotlin. Is it broken or .. improved?</subject>
        <url>https://samara-it-community.timepad.ru/event/845193/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>A story about how we fixed ugly api of android sdk (before google did it with KTX) and completely ruined an average library for integration tests.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-09-12</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-09-12</endDate>
        <location>Kitchener, ON</location>
        <speaker>Dan Rusu, Kyle Platt</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin Waterloo P2P</title>
        <subject>Introduction to Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Kotlin-Waterloo-P2P/events/252746912/</url>
        <content>
            <slides>https://speakerdeck.com/determinant/intro-to-kotlin</slides>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>This is an introduction to the Kotlin programming language. We'll include a brief look at some awesome features of this modern language as well as the many benefits. Kotlin is a free and open source programming language designed by JetBrains. It can be used for Android, JVM server back-end, javascript, as well as native development such as IOS. Come and enjoy some refreshments while we discuss Kotlin, objectives, and plans for this group.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>ru</lang>
        <startDate>2018-08-23</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-08-23</endDate>
        <location>Novosibirsk, Russia</location>
        <speaker>Ilya Matveyev</speaker>
        <title>JUGNsk</title>
        <subject>Kotlin вообще и Native в частности</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/JUGNsk/events/253327525/</url>
        <content>
            <slides>
                https://speakerdeck.com/jugnsk/jugnsk-meetup-number-3-il-ia-matvieiev-kotlin-voobshchie-i-native-v-chastnosti-1
            </slides>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Наверняка многие слышали о таком языке для JVM, как Котлин. Однако далеко не все знают, что он также компилируется в JavaScript или в нативный код для различных платформ. В этом докладе мы постараемся пролить свет на поддержку мультиплатформенных проектов, а также расскажем о том, как мы компилируем Котлин в машинный код, какие сложности при этом встречаются и какие возможности дает это пользователю.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>ru</lang>
        <startDate>2018-08-23</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-08-23</endDate>
        <location>Almaty, Kazakhstan</location>
        <speaker>Janibek Marshal</speaker>
        <title>JDrinkUp Almaty</title>
        <subject>Почему Android разработчики переходят на Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/DrinkUp-Almaty/events/253866558/</url>
        <content>
            <slides>https://speakerdeck.com/johnmars/pochiemu-android-razrabotchiki-pieriekhodiat-na-kotlin</slides>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-10-04</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-10-04</endDate>
        <location>Krakow, Poland</location>
        <speaker>Piotr Ślesarew</speaker>
        <title>MobiConf 2018</title>
        <subject>Magic sugars that can make your Kotlin codebase happier</subject>
        <url>https://2018.mobiconf.org/schedule/</url>
        <content>
            <video>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BGrZbMm1aHY</video>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Kotlin language brings tons of new concepts and features to your miserable programming life and it is really hard to use all of them in your daily duties. After almost two years of using Kotlin in production, the language itself can give me joy and satisfaction.</p>
<p>How is it possible? Because of its many small sweet sugars 🍰. In this talk, I would like to share with you my favorite Kotlin candies that I discovered when I was in need of writing robust and concise components for Android applications.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-10-04</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-10-04</endDate>
        <location>Krakow, Poland</location>
        <speaker>Ivan Morgillo</speaker>
        <title>MobiConf 2018</title>
        <subject>Kotlin coroutines – A story of an old code base, dozens of reactive streams, a new language and a new
            way for concurrency.
        </subject>
        <url>https://2018.mobiconf.org/schedule/</url>
        <content>
            <video>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tOjdn1NDULM</video>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>In a world dominated by RX and Java based code bases, JetBrains introduced Kotlin and coroutines - a simpler way to do multithreading.</p>
<p>This is the story of how I migrated an old project from a monolithic Java mess with improperly used RxJava to a cleaner architecture, based on Kotlin, coroutines and common sense.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>ja</lang>
        <startDate>2018-08-25</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-08-25</endDate>
        <location>Tokio, Japan</location>
        <speaker>Toshihiro Yagi</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin Fest 2018</title>
        <subject>Kotlin コルーチンを 理解しよう</subject>
        <url>https://kotlin.connpass.com/event/91666/</url>
        <content>
            <slides>https://speakerdeck.com/sys1yagi/kotlin-korutinwo-li-jie-siyou</slides>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>ja</lang>
        <startDate>2018-08-25</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-08-25</endDate>
        <location>Tokio, Japan</location>
        <speaker>Akinori Yamada</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin Fest 2018</title>
        <subject>Kotlin で愛でる Microservices</subject>
        <url>https://kotlin.connpass.com/event/91666/</url>
        <content>
            <slides>https://speakerdeck.com/stormcat24/kotlin-fest</slides>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-08-29</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-08-29</endDate>
        <location>Tallinn, Estonia</location>
        <speaker>Anton Arhipov</speaker>
        <title>Advanced Java Estonia</title>
        <subject>Kotlin DSL in 60 minutes</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Advanced-Java-Estonia/events/253565335/</url>
        <content>
            <video>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lLUo5daDgAc</video>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Learn how to create type-safe and statically typed DSLs in Kotlin. The session starts with an introduction to DSL related Kotlin language features. Next, we create a simple DSL in a live coding session and then continue adding expressiveness and language features. We cover a number of examples, like JSON or XML builder's, data binding, configuration & template engines</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-09-13</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-09-13</endDate>
        <location>Tel Aviv-Yafo, Israel</location>
        <speaker>Ohad Shai</speaker>
        <title>KotlinTLV</title>
        <subject>Klean that Code, Boil those Boilerplates</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/KotlinTLV/events/254246117/</url>
        <content>
            <slides>https://speakerdeck.com/oshai/klean-that-code-boil-those-boilerplates</slides>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-09-13</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-09-13</endDate>
        <location>Tel Aviv-Yafo, Israel</location>
        <speaker>Yair Palti</speaker>
        <title>KotlinTLV</title>
        <subject>Static &amp; Singleton in Java vs Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/KotlinTLV/events/254246117/</url>
        <content>
            <slides>https://speakerdeck.com/yairp/static-and-singleton-in-java-vs-kotlin</slides>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-10-20</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-10-20</endDate>
        <location>Lugano (Ticino), Switzerland</location>
        <speaker>Marharyta Nedzelska</speaker>
        <title>Voxxed Days Ticino 2018</title>
        <subject>Kotlin: lazy language for lazy people</subject>
        <url>https://cfpvdt18.confinabox.com/talk/HIC-9228</url>
        <content>
            <video>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xTYKuI4HSWc</video>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>A few years ago you had to work hard to succeed in some fields. Nowadays you don’t need to work hard but to work smart. So this means that most of the time laziness (of course not extremely) is useful for our productivity. On the other hand, laziness is extremely important when you work with a large amount of data and reduced space or power. In this talk we will try to cover all aspects of laziness in Kotlin: starting from lazy initialization of properties using delegates, lazy collections, sequences and, finally, laziness with coroutines. The main thing we would like to talk about is how to use this laziness and be productive with it. To see one more benefit of laziness in Kotlin we’ll refactor a real application to use lazy calculations.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-09-18</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-09-18</endDate>
        <location>Utrecht, Netherlands</location>
        <speaker>Paulien van Alst</speaker>
        <title>Utrecht Java User Group</title>
        <subject>How to build a Kotlin enterprise application.</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Utrecht-Java-User-Group/events/250843631/</url>
        <content>
            <slides>https://github.com/utrechtjug/slides/blob/master/180918_KotlinWorkshop.pdf</slides>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Kotlin is the new JVM language where all the best practices of programming come together. Looking forward to discover a language that will support you in writing readable and understandable code in the fewest lines possible? Without any help of any extra libraries such as Lombok, Guava and even more, Kotlin will challenge you to write code that even the business analyst should be able to understand. With Kotlin you can finally focus on the business features you want to implement instead working on the language itself. In this workshop, you will build a simple webservice in Kotlin and hopefully see how easy it can be to write new business functionality.
- Exercise 1 : (data) classes, collections and types
- Exercise 2 : inheritance, interfaces and extension functions
- Exercise 3 : how to integrate Kotlin with Spring</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>ja</lang>
        <startDate>2018-09-11</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-09-11</endDate>
        <location>Tokyo, Japan</location>
        <speaker>Taro Nagasava</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin Fest 2018</title>
        <subject>How to Test Server-side Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://connpass.com/event/100752/</url>
        <content>
            <slides>https://speakerdeck.com/ntaro/how-to-test-server-side-kotlin</slides>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-09-17</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-09-17</endDate>
        <location>Dublin, Ireland</location>
        <speaker>Tomás Hanley</speaker>
        <title>Dublin Kotlin User Group</title>
        <subject>Asynchronous Kotlin Web Server with Ktor</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Dublin-Kotlin-User-Group/</url>
        <content>
            <slides>https://slides.com/tomashanley/kotlin-intro-starting-the-koans-4-7-8/#/</slides>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>In this session, we’re going to explore how to create a standalone server application using Ktor. We'll work through a series of exercises to get familiar with Ktor, with the idea of build a web service for ordering food for our drone delivery app.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-09-22</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-09-22</endDate>
        <location>Vienna, Austria</location>
        <speaker>Lukas Lechner</speaker>
        <title>droidcon Vienna 2018</title>
        <subject>How 'Effective Java' influenced Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://droidcon.at/schedule/#session-112</url>
        <content>
            <slides>https://speakerdeck.com/lukle/how-effective-java-influenced-kotlin</slides>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>One of the most popular Java books is 'Effective Java' from Joshua Bloch, which describes how to avoid common mistakes, how to deal with Java's weaknesses, and how best practices for the language look like. When Jetbrains started to create a 'better Java' with Kotlin, a lot of ideas about how to make a better language came from the information of 'Effective Java' and lots of design decisions are based on the book. In this talk the audience will learn how the book influenced the language design and the compiler of Kotlin and in what way the book is deeply ingrained into the language.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-10-07</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-10-07</endDate>
        <location>Minsk, Belarus</location>
        <speaker>Marcin Moskala</speaker>
        <title>Mobile Optimazed 2018</title>
        <subject>Kotlin Coroutines in action</subject>
        <url>https://moconf.by/#talk_android_moskala</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Kotlin Coroutines fascinate from its early beta. They are a new way to write asynchronous and non-blocking code. They can be thought of as light-weight threads without having to deal with all the problems that threads bring to the table.</p>
<p>In this talk Marcin will show how to use Kotlin Coroutines and what makes them so special and so efficient. He will also discuss if they are an alternative to RxJava.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>ru</lang>
        <startDate>2018-09-06</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-09-06</endDate>
        <location>Minsk, Belarus</location>
        <speaker>Sergey Kryukov</speaker>
        <title>Belarus Kotlin User Group</title>
        <subject>Введение в OPENRNDR</subject>
        <url>https://bkug.by/</url>
        <content>
            <video>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5UPO553U-w4</video>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Продолжаю тему “нецелевого” использования языка Kotlin. В этот раз поговорим об OPENRNDR — фреймворке для креативного программирования, как убеждают его авторы. Так ли это? Проверим на практике.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>ru</lang>
        <startDate>2018-09-06</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-09-06</endDate>
        <location>Minsk, Belarus</location>
        <speaker>Roman Artemiev</speaker>
        <title>Belarus Kotlin User Group</title>
        <subject>Kotlin/JS</subject>
        <url>https://bkug.by/</url>
        <content>
            <video>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X4-GgdAG0ZM</video>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>В докладе речь пойдет про Kotlin/JS, я расскажу что это такое и зачем нужно в контексте Kotlin MPP (Multiplatform Projects). Покопаемся под капотом у компилятора, познакомимся с полезными инструментами для разработки на Kotlin/JS. Немного затронем будущее этого направления языка, а также постараемся ответить на самые волнующие сообщество вопросы. Приходите, будет интересно!</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>fr</lang>
        <startDate>2018-10-03</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-10-03</endDate>
        <location>Paris, France</location>
        <speaker>Sergio Dos Santos, Benjamin Lacroix</speaker>
        <title>Le Mois Du Kotlin</title>
        <subject>Kotlin ? D’accord, mais aide moi à convaincre mon PO !</subject>
        <url>https://le-mois-du-kotlin.xebia.fr/#schedule</url>
        <content>
            <video>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LdHVbhcPxNc</video>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Kotlin fait petit à petit son chemin dans les entreprises, et pas seulement sur Android ! Quels sont les avantages du langage par rapport à Java, par rapport aux autres langages back-end et même par rapport à Javascript ? D'où vient Kotlin ? Faut-il migrer les applications et former les équipiers ? Peut-on réaliser des applications de qualité, qui dureront dans le temps ? Quels sont les outils à notre disposition ?
Si vous vous posez toutes ces questions, ou si vous souhaitez seulement en savoir plus sur ce prochain langage d'importance, venez, cette conférence est faite pour vous !</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>fr</lang>
        <startDate>2018-10-03</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-10-03</endDate>
        <location>Paris, France</location>
        <speaker>Simone Civetta</speaker>
        <title>Le Mois Du Kotlin</title>
        <subject>Frameworks multi-plateformes partagés avec Kotlin / Native</subject>
        <url>https://le-mois-du-kotlin.xebia.fr/#schedule</url>
        <content>
            <video>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=avGd1PJqKZE</video>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Bien que la création d'applications inter-plates-formes complètes puisse souvent s'avérer être une mauvaise idée, une logique spécifique à un client peut grandement bénéficier d'un code unique, permettant à la fois d'écrire et de tester le code. Depuis fin 2016, Kotlin/Native peut compiler du code Kotlin sous une forme binaire, qui peut ensuite être intégrée dans une application native. Dans cette présentation, vous apprendrez pourquoi il est logique et efficace d'exploiter ces fonctionnalités expérimentales et de créer un module multi-plateforme réutilisable sur Android et iOS.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-14</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-14</endDate>
        <location>Helwan, Egypt</location>
        <speaker>Shady Yehia Selim</speaker>
        <title>GDG Helwan</title>
        <subject>Kotlin Surprises in Google I/O 2018!</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GDG-Helwan/events/250354478/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Collecting all the Kotlin announcements in Google I/O 2018</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>fr</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-29</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-29</endDate>
        <location>Montpellier, France</location>
        <speaker>Didier Plaindoux</speaker>
        <title>Sunny Tech 2018</title>
        <subject>Kotlin Parsec</subject>
        <url>https://sunny-tech.io/schedule/day1</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Un Parsec est bien connu pour mesurer la distance à laquelle se trouve une étoile dont la parallaxe est d'une seconde . Cela vous semble cryptique je vous propose alors plutôt de traiter de Parser Combinator avec Kotlin afin de découvrir certaines facettes du langage comme l'extension de fonction et la construction d'un DSL dédié.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>es</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-24</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-24</endDate>
        <location>Valencia, Spain</location>
        <speaker>Víctor Bolinches</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin MasterClass</title>
        <subject>Desarrollo Multiplataforma con Kotlin</subject>
        <url>http://empretsinf.blogs.upv.es/2018/05/15/anuncion-de-charla-kotlin-masterclass-jueves-24-5-1230/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Kotlin es un lenguaje fuertemente tipado, cross-platform y open source, bajo la licencia Apache 2.0, creado por JetBrains. Su programación es concisa, versátil y segura. Interoperable con Java al 100%, es el lenguaje oficial de Google para aplicaciones Android nativas. Permite desarrollos nativos en sistemas embebidos tales como Windows, Linux, Mac e iOS, así como una fácil programación a través de DSL’s en el marco Web.</p>
<p>Los asistentes a las charla podrán recibir una MasterClass de Kotlin para abordar desarrollos multiplataforma.</p>
<p>Se migrará código de Java a Kotlin para comprender su sintaxis, apoyado con ejemplos de uso.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-16</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-16</endDate>
        <location>Abuja, Nigeria</location>
        <speaker>Akinrolie Slick</speaker>
        <title>KOTLIN NIGHT ABUJA '18</title>
        <subject>Best practices in using Kotlin on Android</subject>
        <url>https://www.eventbrite.com/e/kotlin-night-abuja-18-tickets-43651251067</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>taking the participants through the best possible ways and steps to build Android Apps with Kotlin</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-16</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-16</endDate>
        <location>Abuja, Nigeria</location>
        <speaker>Adetayo James</speaker>
        <title>KOTLIN NIGHT ABUJA '18</title>
        <subject>Kotlin In Action with Codelab session</subject>
        <url>https://www.eventbrite.com/e/kotlin-night-abuja-18-tickets-43651251067</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-16</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-16</endDate>
        <location>Abuja, Nigeria</location>
        <speaker>Micheal Obi</speaker>
        <title>KOTLIN NIGHT ABUJA '18</title>
        <subject>Kotlin Lang What's in Need with Codelab Session: Api with Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.eventbrite.com/e/kotlin-night-abuja-18-tickets-43651251067</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-16</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-16</endDate>
        <location>Abuja, Nigeria</location>
        <speaker>Ijatuyi Sukanmi</speaker>
        <title>KOTLIN NIGHT ABUJA '18</title>
        <subject>Kotlin On Web</subject>
        <url>https://www.eventbrite.com/e/kotlin-night-abuja-18-tickets-43651251067</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-01</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-01</endDate>
        <location>Athens, Greece</location>
        <speaker>Antonis Lilis</speaker>
        <title>Voxxed Athens 2018</title>
        <subject>Why Kotlin?</subject>
        <url>https://voxxeddays.com/athens/#schedule</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Do you like Java but wish you didn’t have to write so much boilerplate code? Maybe it’s time for a switch. Kotlin aims to address many of the pitfalls that are common with Java development, while making your code more concise, safe, and expressive. It is also 100% interoperable with Java and can be easily mixed in the same project.</p>
<p>In this presentation Antonis will try to guide you through the main features of Kotlin that make it so special and provide a short introduction to the language.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>es</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-06</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-06</endDate>
        <location>Lima, Peru</location>
        <speaker>Bruno Aybar</speaker>
        <title>Perú Kotlin User Group</title>
        <subject>Java to Kotlin: From Zero to Hero</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Peru-Kotlin-User-Group/events/251019272/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>es</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-06</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-06</endDate>
        <location>Lima, Peru</location>
        <speaker>Eduardo José Medina Alfaro</speaker>
        <title>Perú Kotlin User Group</title>
        <subject>Conceptos básicos sobre patrones de arquitectura para Android</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Peru-Kotlin-User-Group/events/251019272/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>es</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-06</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-06</endDate>
        <location>Lima, Peru</location>
        <speaker>Kevin Salazar</speaker>
        <title>Perú Kotlin User Group</title>
        <subject>Kotlin Extensions with Anko and Android KTX</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Peru-Kotlin-User-Group/events/251019272/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>es</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-24</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-24</endDate>
        <location>Eliezer López</location>
        <speaker>Rafa Paradela</speaker>
        <title>GDG Cádiz</title>
        <subject>Introducción a la Programación Funcional con Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/gdgcadiz/events/250319785/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>es</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-24</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-24</endDate>
        <location>Zapopan, Mexico</location>
        <speaker>Alejandro Tellez</speaker>
        <title>Guadalajara Java User Group</title>
        <subject>Consuming Microsoft Excel documents with Apache POI and Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/gdljug/events/250846709/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Apache POI, a project run by the Apache Software Foundation, and previously a sub-project of the Jakarta Project, is a set of libraries used to read and write Microsoft Office documents. We'll be learening how to use it with Kotlin as a language to read and write an Excel file</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-26</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-26</endDate>
        <location>Solo, Indonesia</location>
        <speaker>Nando Septian Husni</speaker>
        <title>Solo Kotlin User Group</title>
        <subject>the first app with your kotlin in android developer</subject>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Introduce using kotlin for android developer</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>es</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-31</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-31</endDate>
        <location>México City, Mexico</location>
        <speaker>David Hackro</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin CDMX User Group</title>
        <subject>How Kotlin it's best option? - From perspective of Java Developer</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Kotlin-CDMX/events/251110278/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>ru</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-26</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-26</endDate>
        <location>Minsk, Belarus</location>
        <speaker>Eugene Petrenko</speaker>
        <title>Voxxeddays Minsk</title>
        <subject>Multiplatform Kotlin In 42 minutes</subject>
        <url>https://voxxeddays.com/minsk/</url>
        <content>
            <slides>https://speakerdeck.com/nightlynexus/getting-kotlin-in-your-codebase</slides>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p> </p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>es</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-30</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-30</endDate>
        <location>Valencia, Spain</location>
        <speaker>Ricardo García Fernández</speaker>
        <title>GDG Valencia</title>
        <subject>Mejora tu código con Sonarqube + Aplicaciones asíncronas con Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GDGValencia/events/250916434/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>de</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-26</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-26</endDate>
        <location>Regensburg,Germany</location>
        <speaker>Tobias Schneck</speaker>
        <title>Hackaburg 2018</title>
        <subject>Kotlin for backend development</subject>
        <url>https://hackaburg.de/</url>
        <content>
            <slides>
                https://www.slideshare.net/TobiasSchneck/kotlin-for-backend-development-hackaburg-2018-regensburg-98785534/
            </slides>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>es</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-31</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-31</endDate>
        <location>México City, Mexico</location>
        <speaker>Leonel Méndez</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin CDMX User Group</title>
        <subject>El sistema de tipos en Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Kotlin-CDMX/events/251110278/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-07-19</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-07-19</endDate>
        <location>Denver, United States</location>
        <speaker>Nick Capurso</speaker>
        <title>360|AnDev July 2018</title>
        <subject>Kotlin Coroutines: An Intro to Practical Use on Android</subject>
        <url>https://360andev.com/sessions/kotlin-coroutines-an-intro-to-practical-use-on-android/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Asynchronous programming has always been a challenging problem for Android developers. Any good solution has to gracefully handle errors, cancellation, chaining multiple actions together, handle thread swapping, and much more.</p>
<p>Kotlin’s coroutines are yet another option for asynchronous programming. However, unlike other popular contenders, coroutines meet all the previously mentioned requirements out-of-the-box, have a gentler learning curve, and don’t require you to write an absurd amount of boilerplate.</p>
<p>That said, learning any new asynchronous solution takes time and often comes with a period of trial-and-error until you have all the nuances figured out. Get a jumpstart on coroutines:</p>
<p>(1) Lessen the learning curve by getting the subtleties of coroutines out of the way early
(2) Learn how to work coroutines into an existing app: easy places to start transitioning, interop with existing libraries, and reusing existing threading constructs
(3) Learn how to easily support error handling, cancellation, and task chaining
(4) Learn how to unit test coroutines</p>
<p>Get a head start on coroutines in your apps and easily write, test, and maintain asynchronous code like never before!</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-07-20</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-07-20</endDate>
        <location>Denver, United States</location>
        <speaker>Oluwasegun Famisa</speaker>
        <title>360|AnDev July 2018</title>
        <subject>Kotlin, Beyond the Basics</subject>
        <url>https://360andev.com/sessions/kotlin-beyond-the-basics/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>In this talk, we will look at how you should not do things with Kotlin. For example, we will talk about misusing scoping functions like “let”, “run”, “apply”, etc. and learn the right time to use which one while not overusing them. We will also talk about interoperability between Kotlin and Java. We will look at how not to do things when building APIs that may be consumed in Java – things like top-level constant declaration vs constants within companion objects, making use Jvm* annotations in Kotlin vs not using them.</p>
<p>We will also talk about platform types and the potential harm they pose when calling Java code from Kotlin. We will also address another commonly overlooked topic – the fact that Kotlin encourages a new paradigm of programming where you’re not thinking in terms of steps (imperative) but rather, in terms of functions applied to parameters (functional programming) and we still find ourselves doing things the wrong way.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-07-20</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-07-20</endDate>
        <location>Denver, United States</location>
        <speaker>Joshua Lamson</speaker>
        <title>360|AnDev July 2018</title>
        <subject>Custom Drawing with Canvas in Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://360andev.com/sessions/custom-drawing-with-canvas-in-kotlin/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>When you’re creating a new View to display some complex data, it’s easy for the number of View objects you’re using to get out of control. Between elaborate shapes, shaders/colors, and text in specific places and orientations, using only Android Views and layouts can turn your layout into a dense, complicated mess. Luckily, there’s a better way to add all your customizations. What you need is a blank Canvas! (Literally, android.graphics.Canvas).</p>
<p>In this session, we’ll delve into the details of using a Canvas to display anything you need in a truly custom way, explaining it all through simple examples written in Kotlin. You’ll leave this talk knowing how override the behavior of View, ViewGroup, and Drawable to draw custom shapes, paths, and text on the Canvas.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-14</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-14</endDate>
        <location>Prague, Czech Republic</location>
        <speaker>Eugene Petrenko</speaker>
        <title>CZ Kotlin User Group</title>
        <subject>Multiplatform Kotlin in 42 minutes</subject>
        <url>https://www.eventbrite.com/e/cz-kotlin-meetup-4-tickets-46459595902?utm-medium=discovery&amp;utm-campaign=social&amp;utm-content=attendeeshare&amp;aff=estw&amp;utm-source=tw&amp;utm-term=listing</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>cz</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-14</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-14</endDate>
        <location>Prague, Czech Republic</location>
        <speaker>Petr Balat</speaker>
        <title>CZ Kotlin User Group</title>
        <subject>Kotlin a Spring Framework/Spring Boot</subject>
        <url>https://www.eventbrite.com/e/cz-kotlin-meetup-4-tickets-46459595902?utm-medium=discovery&amp;utm-campaign=social&amp;utm-content=attendeeshare&amp;aff=estw&amp;utm-source=tw&amp;utm-term=listing</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>ru</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-12</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-12</endDate>
        <location>Minsk, Belarus</location>
        <speaker>Sergey Sitko</speaker>
        <title>GDG Minsk</title>
        <subject>Разбираемся с Kotlin coroutines</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GDG-Minsk/events/251263252/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Общий подход асинхронного программирования. Короткое ревью возможностей Java concurrent API, RxJava, Android API. Знакомство с Kotlin Coroutine. Что такое coroutine, как это чудо создавать и как им пользоваться.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-01</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-01</endDate>
        <location>Kampala, Uganda</location>
        <speaker>Brian</speaker>
        <title>GDG Kampala</title>
        <subject>Android Things and Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GDG-Kampala/events/251255643/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>In this talk, Brian tells us about the latest and greatest about Kotlin released at Google I/O 2018 and about the development of Sentinel, the first home security robot powered by Android Things, and how hardware, software, coded in Kotlin, Firebase and how the Google Cloud Platform integrates with Sentinel to "bring it to life".</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-01</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-01</endDate>
        <location>Kampala, Uganda</location>
        <speaker>Johnstone</speaker>
        <title>GDG Kampala</title>
        <subject>Kotlin Multiplatform Projects</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GDG-Kampala/events/251255643/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>A Kotlin multiplatform project allows you share code between different platforms. It takes a different approach to cross platform development than Xamarin and other frameworks. This talk will be about how to setup and build a multiplatform project. We will look at features of Kotlin multiplatform development through an example project. We will also look at the current limitations.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-01</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-01</endDate>
        <location>Vienna, Austria</location>
        <speaker>Christoph Pickl, Riccardo ten Cate</speaker>
        <title>defdev.eu/vienna</title>
        <subject>Kotlin introduction + Automated security testing in CI/CD pipeline (an intro)</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/defdev-vie/events/251000578/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-05</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-05</endDate>
        <location>Amsterdam, Netherlands</location>
        <speaker>Joost Heijkoop</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin.amsterdam</title>
        <subject>Kotlin Case Studies</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/kotlin-amsterdam/events/251189211/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>es</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-14</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-14</endDate>
        <location>Santiago, Chile</location>
        <speaker>Joost Heijkoop</speaker>
        <title>GDG Android Santiago</title>
        <subject>What's Kotlin and Why should you use it?</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/gdg-android-santiago/events/251192922/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>es</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-14</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-14</endDate>
        <location>Santiago, Chile</location>
        <speaker>Harttin Arce</speaker>
        <title>GDG Android Santiago</title>
        <subject>Kotlin + Room for Dummies</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/gdg-android-santiago/events/251192922/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>ja</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-30</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-30</endDate>
        <location>Tokyo, Japan</location>
        <speaker>Fukui Atsuko</speaker>
        <title>集まれKotlin好き！Kotlin愛好会 vol1</title>
        <subject>こんな時どう書くの？ 逆引きKotlin入門</subject>
        <url>https://love-kotlin.connpass.com/event/86390/</url>
        <content>
            <slides>https://speakerdeck.com/muumuumuumuu/konnashi-doushu-kufalse-ni-yin-kikotlinru-men</slides>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>ja</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-30</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-30</endDate>
        <location>Tokyo, Japan</location>
        <speaker>Sasami</speaker>
        <title>「集まれKotlin好き！Kotlin愛好会 vol1</title>
        <subject>How to Kotlin のセッションからKotlinらしい表現を学ぶ</subject>
        <url>https://love-kotlin.connpass.com/event/86390/</url>
        <content>
            <slides>https://speakerdeck.com/sasamihoo/learn-how-to-kotlin</slides>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>ru</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-20</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-20</endDate>
        <location>Moscow, Russia</location>
        <speaker>Sergey Krukov</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin Moscow</title>
        <subject>Kotlin/Native Sneak Peek</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/KotlinMoscow/events/250681145/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p> </p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>ru</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-20</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-20</endDate>
        <location>Moscow, Russia</location>
        <speaker>Svyatoslav Shcherbyna</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin Moscow</title>
        <subject>Kotlin/Native: что, как, зачем и почему</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/KotlinMoscow/events/250681145/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p> </p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>es</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-05</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-05</endDate>
        <location>Bogotá, Colombia</location>
        <speaker>Juan Guillermo Gómez</speaker>
        <title>GDG Bogotá</title>
        <subject>Creando tu backend con Kotlin y GCP</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/gdgbogota/events/251192993/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Klotin un nuevo lenguaje que corre sobre la JVM, moderno y multiplataforma. Se habla mucho de kotlin a nivel de apps, pero es posible crear backends con el. En este meetup crearemos un microservicio con kotlin, usando frameworks de la industria, con clean architecture y lo desplegaremos en Google Cloud Platform.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>tr</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-05</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-05</endDate>
        <location>Istanbul, Turkey</location>
        <speaker>Hadi Tok</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin Istanbul</title>
        <subject>Android projesini Kotlin'e dönüştürme</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Kotlin-%C4%B0stanbul/events/250871440/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Bu etkinliğimizde Hadi Tok bizlere varolan android uygulamalarımızda kullandığımız Java dilinin kotlin ile beraber kullanımı, Java kodlarının Kotlin'e dönüştürülmesi ve bu geçişte karşılaşılan genel problemler ve bu problemlerin çözüm yollarından bahsedecek.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-05</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-05</endDate>
        <location>São Paulo, Brazil</location>
        <speaker>Ubiratan Soares</speaker>
        <title>GDG-SP</title>
        <subject>Kotlin workshop</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GDG-SP/events/251018475/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-06</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-06</endDate>
        <location>San Diego, CA</location>
        <speaker>Joshua Bloch.</speaker>
        <title>San Diego Kotlin User Group</title>
        <subject>Monthly Kotlin! - Effective Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/sd-kotlin/events/251387669/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>es</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-06</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-06</endDate>
        <location>Madrid, Spain</location>
        <speaker>Sobre Raúl</speaker>
        <title>MadridJUG</title>
        <subject>Programación funcional en Kotlin con Arrow</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/MadridJUG/events/251046516/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>es</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-06</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-06</endDate>
        <location>Lima, Peru</location>
        <speaker>Jose Quispe Irrazábal</speaker>
        <title>Perú Kotlin User Group</title>
        <subject>Conceptos básicos sobre patrones de arquitectura para Android</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Peru-Kotlin-User-Group/events/251019272/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>nl</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-07</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-07</endDate>
        <location>Utrecht, Netherlands</location>
        <speaker>Urs Peter</speaker>
        <title>Utrecht Kotlin Meetup</title>
        <subject>From Java to Kotlin in 60 minutes</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/meetup-group-YgJEOzCn/events/251042505/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>In de eerste sessie zal Urs Peter via live-coding laten zien hoe makkelijk het is om van Java naar Kotlin over te stappen en welke voordelen daarbij komen kijken. Hij maakt gebruik van Java code snippets, die stapsgewijs worden omgezet naar Kotlin terwijl de belangrijkste taal features toegelicht worden. Tot slot licht hij toe hoe je Kotlin succesvol in je organisatie kunt introduceren op basis van de ervaringen die hij heeft opgedaan bij Coin.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-07</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-07</endDate>
        <location>Amsterdam, Netherlands</location>
        <speaker>Alexey Soshin</speaker>
        <title>GOTO Nights Amsterdam</title>
        <subject>Concurrency with VertX in Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GOTO-Nights-Amsterdam/events/248885105/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>In this talk we'll discuss how to write highly concurrent web scrapper on top of Vert.x and Kotlin. Let's assume you want to have the entire LOLcatz archive on your laptop. That's thousands of pages you need to parse, to get those funny picture URL's from, then actually download them. I plan to demonstrate how the asynchronous model of Vert.x can help us with this very important tasks and get the maximum from your hardware. Also in this talk, some more serious stuff: pipelines, worker verticles, the EventBus and asynchronous work with the file system.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-07</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-07</endDate>
        <location>Zagreb, Croatia</location>
        <speaker>Branimir Akmadža</speaker>
        <title>Infinum Android Talks / Zagreb</title>
        <subject>UI Tests and Kotlin Robots</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Infinum-Android-Talks-Zagreb/events/251105758/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>When I first started to implement UI tests in my project, I thought to myself "What a huge amount of code for something so simple - I only need to check if my image is really shown". After some time spent on research, I discovered a very nice pattern that is possible to set up in Kotlin - DSL robots. In this talk I will show you how that Kotlin sorcery looks like, and why you should (or should not) implement UI tests!</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>it</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-08</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-08</endDate>
        <location>Torino, Italy</location>
        <speaker>Leonardo Pirro</speaker>
        <title>GDG Torino</title>
        <subject>Better Async With Kotlin Coroutines</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GDG-Torino/events/248902996/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>In questo talk scopriremo i principi base delle coroutines e quanto è semplice implementarle nei nostri progetti.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>it</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-08</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-08</endDate>
        <location>Fabio Collini</location>
        <speaker>Leonardo Pirro</speaker>
        <title>GDG Torino</title>
        <subject>Async code on Kotlin: RxJava or/and co-routines</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GDG-Torino/events/248902996/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Impareremo a scrivere codice asincrono con RxJava e le altre librerie ReactiveX</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>it</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-08</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-08</endDate>
        <location>Omar Miatello</location>
        <speaker>Leonardo Pirro</speaker>
        <title>GDG Torino</title>
        <subject>Google Cloud Functions: try{ Kotlin } instead Of Javascript</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GDG-Torino/events/248902996/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>I primi passi per iniziare a scrivere le Cloud Functions for Firebase utilizzando Kotlin/JS per realizzare la backend</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>it</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-08</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-08</endDate>
        <location>Roberto Orgiu</location>
        <speaker>Leonardo Pirro</speaker>
        <title>GDG Torino</title>
        <subject>Escape from Java" Scopriremo come passare da Java a Kotlin in pochi passaggi</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GDG-Torino/events/248902996/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Durante l’evento saranno presenti tanti gadget per i partecipanti e il servizio di catering gentilmente offerto da Synesthesia.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-09</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-09</endDate>
        <location>Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia</location>
        <speaker>Amr Mohsen, Harsh Mittal</speaker>
        <title>Google Developer Group Kuala Lumpur - GDGKL</title>
        <subject>Introduction to Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GDGKualaLumpur/events/251223746/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>We'll have a tech talk then a workshop where you will learn the basics of Kotlin, create an Android app using it, and you will see why you should make the switch from Java to Kotlin.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-26</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-26</endDate>
        <location>Semarang, Indonesia</location>
        <speaker>Kalif Ardy Noerwicaksono</speaker>
        <title>Google Developer Group Kuala Lumpur - GDGKL</title>
        <subject>Sandec Weekly Training #53 Bassic Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.dicoding.com/events/1694</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>At SANDEC Weekly Training # 53 this time, we will learn about the (new) language used in creating Android app, which is KOTLIN. a new multi-purpose programming language developed by JetBrains.</p>
<p>In this workshop, my friends will know what the difference when we use Kotlin in making an application in android. This workshop will be filled by Mas Kalif Ardi N - One of the trainers at SANDEC.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-30</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-30</endDate>
        <location>Lahore, Pakistan</location>
        <speaker>Mehmood Asghar</speaker>
        <title>Google Developer Group Kuala Lumpur - GDGKL</title>
        <subject>Want know about kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://developer.android.com/kotlin/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>I want to know about kotlin, as I am a developer.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-12</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-12</endDate>
        <location>Toronto, ON</location>
        <speaker>Serhiy Shyyko</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin Toronto</title>
        <subject>Building frontend with Kotlin webpack and React</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Kotlin-Toronto/events/250880050/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>In this talk you’ll learn how to you to build and deploy a Kotlin react frontend application using webpack and kotlin-frontend-plugin. We’ll write a simple backend via Ktor and deploy it all on one of the cloud service providers.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-12</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-12</endDate>
        <location>Chicago, IL</location>
        <speaker>Michael Maletich</speaker>
        <title>Chicago Kotlin Users Group</title>
        <subject>Validating Data at Scale with Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Chicago-Kotlin/events/249196057/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>It's practically a given that data coming into your application will be inconsistent and poorly formatted for your purposes. The best way to handle bad data is to create a strict schema before capturing it. In this talk, you will learn how to improve the quality of data flowing from legacy sources with Kotlin and Baleen, an open source library.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-12</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-12</endDate>
        <location>Melbourne, Australia</location>
        <speaker>Kon Soulianidis</speaker>
        <title>Melbourne Java &amp; JVM Users Group</title>
        <subject>Lean Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Chicago-Kotlin/events/249196057/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-12</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-12</endDate>
        <location>Frankfurt, Germany</location>
        <speaker>Gustav Karlsson</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin Meetup Rhein-Main</title>
        <subject>Dealing with time in Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Kotlin-Rhein-Main/events/250605620/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-12</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-12</endDate>
        <location>Frankfurt, Germany</location>
        <speaker>Ralf Stuckert</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin Meetup Rhein-Main</title>
        <subject>Kotlin-React</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Kotlin-Rhein-Main/events/250605620/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>de</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-12</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-12</endDate>
        <location>Frankfurt, Germany</location>
        <speaker>Guido Dolfen, Timm Hirsens</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin Meetup Rhein-Main</title>
        <subject>Von Java Legacy zu Kotlin Multi-Plattform – Ein Erfahrungsbericht aus der Praxis</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Kotlin-Rhein-Main/events/250605620/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>fr</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-12</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-12</endDate>
        <location>Toulouse, France</location>
        <speaker>Kevin Davin</speaker>
        <title>Toulouse Java User Group</title>
        <subject>Deep Dive Kotlin: du Hello World au Bytecode</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Toulouse-Java-User-Group/events/250956533/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-12</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-12</endDate>
        <location>Singapore, Singapore</location>
        <speaker>Andrey Mischenko</speaker>
        <title>Singapore Kotlin User group</title>
        <subject>What’s next? New features of upcoming Kotlin 1.3</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/kotlinsg/events/251369236/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>What should we expect from the 3rd big release of Kotlin?
Sneak peak on new features, changes and improvements of Kotlin 1.3 before the official announcement and beta version.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-12</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-12</endDate>
        <location>Singapore, Singapore</location>
        <speaker>Vladislav Kan, Alexander Sukharev</speaker>
        <title>Singapore Kotlin User group</title>
        <subject>Kotlin Code Generation</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/kotlinsg/events/251369236/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Learn how to use modern programming technics to avoid writing boilerplate code.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-13</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-13</endDate>
        <location>Vienna, Austria</location>
        <speaker>Christoph Leiter, Christoph Pickl</speaker>
        <title>From Kotlin Vienna</title>
        <subject>Kotlin for beginners - 101 talk and Koans hands-on</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Kotlin-Vienna/events/251396611/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>ou will hear the basics of the Kotlin programming language in a introductionary talk, no Kotlin experience required, Java highly recommended, at least some other general purpose object oriented language (C#, Scala, Ruby, ...)</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-07-20</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-07-20</endDate>
        <location>Denver, CO</location>
        <speaker>Joshua Lamson</speaker>
        <title>From Kotlin Vienna</title>
        <subject>Custom Drawing with Canvas in Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://360andev.com/sessions/custom-drawing-with-canvas-in-kotlin/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>When you’re creating a new View to display some complex data, it’s easy for the number of View objects you’re using to get out of control. Between elaborate shapes, shaders/colors, and text in specific places and orientations, using only Android Views and layouts can turn your layout into a dense, complicated mess. Luckily, there’s a better way to add all your customizations. What you need is a blank Canvas! (Literally, android.graphics.Canvas).</p>
<p>In this session, we’ll delve into the details of using a Canvas to display anything you need in a truly custom way, explaining it all through simple examples written in Kotlin. You’ll leave this talk knowing how override the behavior of View, ViewGroup, and Drawable to draw custom shapes, paths, and text on the Canvas.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-20</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-20</endDate>
        <location>Salzburg, Austria</location>
        <speaker>Christian Ortner</speaker>
        <title>Salzburg Web Dev</title>
        <subject>Kotlin everywhere</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/salzburgwebdev/events/250207767/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-26</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-26</endDate>
        <location>Seoul, Korea (South)</location>
        <speaker>Hadi Hariri</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin Korea</title>
        <subject>Kotlin을 사용한 비동기 프로그래밍(Asynchronous Programming with Kotlin)</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/kotlinkr/events/251399066/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-26</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-26</endDate>
        <location>Prague, Czech Republic</location>
        <speaker>Vladimir Valouch, Jan Dedecek</speaker>
        <title>Prague Mobile Development Meetup</title>
        <subject>How to use TensorFlow on your phone and Kotlin idioms in practice</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Prague-Mobile-Development-Meetup/events/251672580/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Machine Learning on mobile devices with usage of TensorFlow, and the 2nd part of the meetup will be about idioms in Kotlin.
</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>fr</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-22</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-22</endDate>
        <location>Luxembourg, Luxembourg</location>
        <speaker>Philippe Charrière</speaker>
        <title>Voxxed Days Luxembourg</title>
        <subject>Mais LOL, pourquoi avoir inventé Kotlin, Scala est déjà un Java simplifié</subject>
        <url>
            https://cfp-voxxed-lux.yajug.org/2018/talk/AAF-2167/Mais_LOL,_pourquoi_avoir_invente_Kotlin,_Scala_est_deja_un_Java_simplifie
        </url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-09</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-09</endDate>
        <location>Gomel, Belarus</location>
        <speaker>Ales Tsvil</speaker>
        <title>Storm the Front Meetup #1</title>
        <subject>Kotlin is Here Again!</subject>
        <url>https://events.epam.com/events/gomel-front-end-meetup-1</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>I want to tell you about one of the modern and trending languages of today - Kotlin, which among other cool features, has JS compilation target. So if it is possible to use Kotlin today - definitely yes! And I'll show you why =)</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>de</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-14</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-14</endDate>
        <location>Hamburg, Germany</location>
        <speaker>Christophe Beyls</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin User Group Hamburg</title>
        <subject>Kotlin's hidden costs, revisited</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Kotlin-User-Group-Hamburg/events/251261120/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Kotlin has become the new default modern programming language for many Android and backend developers. But exactly how much performance and code size are we sacrificing for making use of all the additional features this language provides compared to Java?
We'll study the Java bytecode generated by the Kotlin compiler in various scenarios in order to find out which code constructs come with hidden performance penalties and learn how to become better Kotlin programmers. Some significant improvements in the recent versions of Kotlin will also be highlighted.
This talk is based on the series of blog posts from the speaker and extends it in some areas.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>de</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-14</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-14</endDate>
        <location>Hamburg, Germany</location>
        <speaker>Niklas Baudy</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin User Group Hamburg</title>
        <subject>Kotlin on Code Quality Tools</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Kotlin-User-Group-Hamburg/events/251261120/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Some might have heard about code quality tools such as Checkstyle, PMD, Findbugs, Lint, Detekt and others but which ones are applicable to Kotlin? I'll list a bunch of tools, explain what they can do, touch on how they work and most importantly show you how you can start using them to be more productive and save a lot of time. With the help of these analyzers you can focus on coding conventions in your team, catch a few bugs and concentrate on what really matters when reviewing code</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-14</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-14</endDate>
        <location>Cambridge, MA</location>
        <speaker>Anton Spaans</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin Office Hours</title>
        <subject>Weaponize your Functional Kotlin with an Arro</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/kotlin-office-hours/events/251200468/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>This talk is an introduction of how you can apply basic functional data types into your Kotlin applications. We will introduce concepts of functional programming and the basic functional data types provided by the Arrow library and show examples on how to use it all in your applications</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-14</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-14</endDate>
        <location>Cambridge, MA</location>
        <speaker>Patrick Beagan</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin Office Hours</title>
        <subject>Let, Also, With, Apply, Run</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/kotlin-office-hours/events/251200468/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>If you've ever seen kotlin code with words like "let, also, with, apply, run" thrown in and wondered what they're for, we'll cover them in this talk. We'll go over the basic usages of each of these standard library functions, the patterns that they can supplement, and how to extend their functionality to help consolidate your code!
</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-14</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-14</endDate>
        <location>Lehi, UT</location>
        <speaker>Jordan Hansen</speaker>
        <title>GDG Silicon Slopes</title>
        <subject>Kotlin Coroutines</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GDG-Silicon-Slopes/events/250912410/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>no</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-18</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-18</endDate>
        <location>Oslo, Norway</location>
        <speaker>Thomas Pettersen</speaker>
        <title>Oslo Kotlin Meetup</title>
        <subject>Kotlin på Android = &lt;3</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/meetup-group-nWeRbyMu/events/251123351/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Hei alle sammen! Nå er det tid for den første Kotlin-meetupen, og det er bare å glede seg. I dag skal vi høre Thomas Pettersen snakke om hvor mye Kotlin forenkler livet vårt når det gjelder utvikling for Android. Det blir lett servering med pizza og brus, og muligheter til mingling og diskusjoner etter foredraget.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>it</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-18</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-18</endDate>
        <location>Pisa, Italy</location>
        <speaker>Domenico Blanco</speaker>
        <title>GDG Pisa</title>
        <subject>KotlinLab</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GDG-Pisa/events/251621352/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>hg</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-18</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-18</endDate>
        <location>Budapest, Hungary</location>
        <speaker>Varga Balázs</speaker>
        <title>HWSW free!</title>
        <subject>Kotlin multiplatform vs testing</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/hwswfree/events/251298043/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>hg</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-18</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-18</endDate>
        <location>Budapest, Hungary</location>
        <speaker>Fuszenecker Zsombor</speaker>
        <title>HWSW free!</title>
        <subject>A Kotlin nyelv kifejezőképessége okozhat meglepetéseket</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/hwswfree/events/251298043/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-19</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-19</endDate>
        <location>Berlin, Germany</location>
        <speaker>Karolina Kafel</speaker>
        <title>Women Techmakers Berlin</title>
        <subject>Study Jam Kickoff + Introduction to Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Women-Techmakers-Berlin/events/250511743/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>On this last session we will give you time to work a bit more on your projects, then we will encourage you to present them :-) It does not matter if it does not work or it is incomplete, what matters is that you tried!</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-19</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-19</endDate>
        <location>Santa Cruz, CA</location>
        <speaker>John Kaster</speaker>
        <title>Santa Cruz Kotlin User Group</title>
        <subject>Kotlin Coroutines: what are they, and why you should love them</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Women-Techmakers-Berlin/events/250511743/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-25</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-25</endDate>
        <location>Berlin, Germany</location>
        <speaker>Ronen Sabag</speaker>
        <title>.droidcon Berlin</title>
        <subject>Lean way to write asynchronous code with Kotlin's coroutines</subject>
        <url>https://www.de.droidcon.com/Sessions/LEAN-WAY-WRITE-ASYNCHRONOUS-CODE-WITH-KOTLIN%E2%80%99S-COROUTINES
        </url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>A very common scenario for a modern app is the need to perform several background tasks in parallel. Sometimes we want to wait for the response of all or some of them and this can be cumbersome to develop. We will see how can we use Kotlin's coroutines power and simplicity to run and manage several tasks in parallel in a very convenient way. This could also be a great and native alternative to RxJava without its steep learning curve and complexity.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-25</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-25</endDate>
        <location>Berlin, Germany</location>
        <speaker>Nelson Osacky</speaker>
        <title>.droidcon Berlin</title>
        <subject>Can Kotlin save me from my groovy buildscripts?</subject>
        <url>https://www.de.droidcon.com/Sessions/CAN-KOTLIN-SAVE-ME-FROM-MY-GROOVY-BUILDSCRIPTS%3F</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>We all know and love to use Kotlin in our Android apps, but did you know you can also use it to write your gradle build scripts? This talk will cover the pros and cons of migrating your buildscripts from Groovy to Kotlin. Is Kotlin more understandable than Groovy? Does it compile faster than Groovy? Is type safety and advantage in build scripts? This talk will also cover how the Kotlin Gradle DSL works under the hood.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-25</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-25</endDate>
        <location>Berlin, Germany</location>
        <speaker>Danny Preussler</speaker>
        <title>.droidcon Berlin</title>
        <subject>To inject or not inject - dependence injection in a Kotlin world</subject>
        <url>https://www.de.droidcon.com/Sessions/TO-INJECT-OR-NOT-INJECT---DEPENDENCY-INJECTION-IN-A-KOTLIN-WORLD</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Dependency Injection via frameworks like Dagger were present in most modern Android projects. But then Kotlin happened. And since then a bunch of new libraries like Koin or Kodein appeared. Developers are even writing articles how to do DI without any framework. Some argue that those don’t even offer real dependency injection. Let’s look at that argument and compare the approaches. So, is there something wrong with Dagger & co. in Kotlin? Are they obsolete? What are the alternatives? Let’s dive in.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-25</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-25</endDate>
        <location>Berlin, Germany</location>
        <speaker>Zan Markan</speaker>
        <title>.droidcon Berlin</title>
        <subject>The state of the Kotlin ecosystem</subject>
        <url>https://www.de.droidcon.com/Sessions/TO-INJECT-OR-NOT-INJECT---DEPENDENCY-INJECTION-IN-A-KOTLIN-WORLD</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Over the last three months I ran a survey of the global Kotlin ecosystem. My goal was to learn how developers use and adopt Kotlin - either in work or side projects, or just for playing around, and what are some of the most popular resources for learning it. The survey was a great success, and gained over 2400 responses in total! The results are meant to become a resource for the Kotlin community. Something we can all look at for interesting insights that will also help drive adoption of Kotlin in our teams and organisations. To give you a taster, here’s a few questions I asked in the survey: How big is Android as a proportion of all Kotlin developers Are people happy naming libraries and tooling with K What are the favourite features of the language What kind of DSLs are people </p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-25</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-25</endDate>
        <location>Berlin, Germany</location>
        <speaker>Ricardo Lage</speaker>
        <title>.droidcon Berlin</title>
        <subject>A deep dive into migrating from avtovalue to Kotlin data classes</subject>
        <url>https://www.de.droidcon.com/Sessions/A-DEEP-DIVE-INTO-MIGRATING-FROM-AUTOVALUE-TO-KOTLIN-DATA-CLASSES</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>AutoValue is a powerful tool provided by Google to generate Java immutable value classes. If you are migrating your project to Kotlin, data classes are the most direct way to replace it while keeping the same features. There are however trade-offs to take into account. In this talk we will introduce how we migrated our project from AutoValue to Kotlin data classes and how we dealt with the issues we encountered along the way. We will also discuss the advantages and disadvantages of each approach in terms of build time, apk size, method count and serialization time. After this introduction, we will deep dive into two topics: First, we will look into different serialization strategies available and how they perform. We will look into Gson, Moshi and Kotlinx.serialization libraries and explore their</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-21</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-21</endDate>
        <location>Salzburg, Austria</location>
        <speaker>Christian Ortner</speaker>
        <title>Salzburg Web Dev</title>
        <subject>Kotlin everywhere - JVM, Android, Javascript</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/salzburgwebdev/events/250207767/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-21</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-21</endDate>
        <location>Lehi, UT</location>
        <speaker>Matt Berteaux</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin Utah</title>
        <subject>Kotlin on the frontend</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Kotlin-Utah/events/250979298/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Did you know that Kotlin can be used for front-end web development? We are going to explore how to do this. Come eat some food and learn more about all that Kotlin can do!</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-21</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-21</endDate>
        <location>Brussels, Belgium</location>
        <speaker>David Gonzalez</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin Belgium User Group</title>
        <subject>Kotlin Summer talk</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Kotlin-User-Group-Belgium/events/251197508/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-27</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-27</endDate>
        <location>Frankfurt, Germany</location>
        <speaker>Volker Benders</speaker>
        <title>Frankfurt AWS User Group</title>
        <subject>Kickstarting AWS with Kotlin and Serverless</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/aws-frankfurt/events/251910783/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-20</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-20</endDate>
        <location>München, Germany</location>
        <speaker>Jossi Wolf</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin User Group Munich - KUG Munich</title>
        <subject>Kotlin JS: An Introduction</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Kotlin-User-Group-Munich/events/251468134/</url>
        <content>
            <slides>https://speakerdeck.com/jossiwolf/js-kug-munich</slides>
            <video>https://www.pscp.tv/w/1zqKVLyjAQVJB</video>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-20</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-20</endDate>
        <location>München, Germany</location>
        <speaker>Dmitry Jemerov</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin User Group Munich - KUG Munich</title>
        <subject>Project Centaur: Using Kotlin to turn IntelliJ IDEA into a server</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Kotlin-User-Group-Munich/events/251468134/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-20</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-20</endDate>
        <location>München, Germany</location>
        <speaker>Werner Keil</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin User Group Munich - KUG Munich</title>
        <subject>Physikal – Using Kotlin for Clean Energy</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Kotlin-User-Group-Munich/events/251468134/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>pl</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-20</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-20</endDate>
        <location>Krakow, Poland</location>
        <speaker>Artur Czopek</speaker>
        <title>Devoxx Poland 2018</title>
        <subject>Do Super Language with Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://cfp.devoxx.pl/2018/talk/NQF-9752/%5B30_min%5D_DSL_-_Do_Super_Language_with_Kotlin</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Kotlin is more powerful every year. This language is great either for imperative and functional programming. However, Kotlin can be used also to creating own Domain-Specified Language. In this session, I will show you how to create your own DSL and use it to create applications even faster with more readable code.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>pl</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-20</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-20</endDate>
        <location>Krakow, Poland</location>
        <speaker>Grzegorz Dyrda</speaker>
        <title>Devoxx Poland 2018</title>
        <subject>Introduction to Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://cfp.devoxx.pl/2018/talk/QER-3823/Introduction_to_Kotlin</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>In this talk I'd like to show You the biggest advantages of Kotlin - a great new programming language for JVM, Web & Native.</p>
<p>I use it for over two years now, and I simply love its readability, elegant solutions of Java’s biggest issues, and vast amount of features that we won’t see in Java anytime soon…</p>
<p>During this talk You'll learn about Kotlin's main characteristics (e.g. null-safety), seamless Java interop, greatest features (e.g. extensions, data classes) etc.</p>
<p>But, most importantly, you'll see that Kotlin is easy to learn and makes you more productive and satisfied as a developer :)</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-07-07</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-07-07</endDate>
        <location>Alexandria, Egypt</location>
        <speaker>Shady Selim</speaker>
        <title>GDG Alexandria</title>
        <subject>Kotlin Updates in from the Google I/O</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GDG-Alexandria/events/247743156/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Will summarize all the Kotlin talks and updates that was mentioned in the Google I/O 2018</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-07-07</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-07-07</endDate>
        <location>Bhubaneswar, India</location>
        <speaker>Sriyank Siddhartha</speaker>
        <title>GDG Bhubaneswar</title>
        <subject>The Power of Kotlin Language</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GDG-Bhubaneswar/events/249694826/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Leverage the power of Koltin with its amazing features and get a sneak peak of its application in Android.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-07-09</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-07-09</endDate>
        <location>Bangalore, India</location>
        <speaker>Chandra Sekhar Nayak</speaker>
        <title>BangaloreJUG</title>
        <subject>Introduction to Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/BangaloreOpenJUG/events/250733205/</url>
        <content>
            <slides>https://speakerdeck.com/chansek/introduction-to-kotlin</slides>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>An introduction to Kotlin for Java developers. This is presented at BangaloreJUG meetup's June 2018 meet.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-26</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-26</endDate>
        <location>London,United Kingdom</location>
        <speaker>Duncan McGregor</speaker>
        <title>London Java Community</title>
        <subject>Refactoring to Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/refactoring-to-kotlin-tickets-46728063897?aff=twsp</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Kotlin neatly fills a gap between the verbosity of Java and the complexity of Scala, has excellent tooling and a fun keyword, so what's not to like?</p>
<p>In this session we introduce the Kotlin language through converting and then refactoring Java code. We’ll code our way through a structured series of exercises designed to familiarise the audience with the features and patterns of the language.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>ko</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-26</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-26</endDate>
        <location>Seoul, Korea (South)</location>
        <speaker>Jaewe Heo</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin Korea Meetup 2018</title>
        <subject>Kotlin-Flavored BuildScripts</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/kotlinkr/events/251399066/</url>
        <content>
            <slides>https://speakerdeck.com/importre/kotlin-flavored-buildscripts</slides>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p># 코틀린 맛 빌드스크립트
코틀린으로 그래들 플러그인을 만들고, 이미 존재하는 그래들 프로젝트에서 사용하는 방법을 소개합니다.
그루비로 되어있는 그래들 프로젝트를 점차 코틀린으로 바꾸는 방향을 제안합니다.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-30</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-30</endDate>
        <location>Bangalore, India</location>
        <speaker>Adit Lal</speaker>
        <title>BlrKotlin - Kotlin User Group</title>
        <subject>Kotlin with Arch Components</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/BlrKotlin/events/251671812/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-30</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-30</endDate>
        <location>Bangalore, India</location>
        <speaker>Suraj Shah</speaker>
        <title>BlrKotlin - Kotlin User Group</title>
        <subject>Idiomatic usage of Operators in Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/BlrKotlin/events/251671812/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-30</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-30</endDate>
        <location>Bangalore, India</location>
        <speaker>Adnan AM</speaker>
        <title>BlrKotlin - Kotlin User Group</title>
        <subject>A Slice of Android Slices</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/BlrKotlin/events/251671812/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>de</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-30</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-30</endDate>
        <location>Karlsruhe, Germany</location>
        <speaker>Hendrik Still, Daniel Bälz</speaker>
        <title>inovex Meetup Karlsruhe</title>
        <subject>Application.kt – Spring Boot 2 mit Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/inovex-karlsruhe/events/249381296/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Die armen mit Java EE geknechteten Backend-Kolleg*innen müssen den ganzen Tag lang Java entwickeln, während die hippen Android-Kolleg*innen ständig am Puls der Zeit sind und mit Kotlin spielen dürfen? Nix da, denn in Spring Boot 2 ist Kotlin ein First-Class Citizen! Deshalb werden wir uns gemeinsam anschauen, welche Änderungen zu beachten sind, was genau gleich bleibt und wie kurz der Code von Beans auf einmal sein kann.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>ja</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-26</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-26</endDate>
        <location>Tokyo, Japan</location>
        <speaker>Yuki Shiho</speaker>
        <title>shibuya.apk #26</title>
        <subject>Kotlin cross-platform / multi-format serialization</subject>
        <url>https://shibuya-apk.connpass.com/event/90517/</url>
        <content>
            <slides>https://speakerdeck.com/shihochan/multi-format-serialization</slides>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-21</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-21</endDate>
        <location>Lille, France</location>
        <speaker>Benjamin Monjoie</speaker>
        <title>Devfest Lille</title>
        <subject>A Kotlink between worlds</subject>
        <url>https://devfest.gdglille.org/#/schedule</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Kotlin is very popular in the Android community but Jetbrains hasn't focused only on the Java related worlds. They have targeted Javascript from the beginning and now they are also broadening their scope to other realms like iOS. Therefore, it's time for you to get acquainted on how you can share code between your projects. That is why, through the help of a little game called</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>fr</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-21</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-21</endDate>
        <location>Lille, France</location>
        <speaker>Grégory Bévan, Thomas Betous</speaker>
        <title>Devfest Lille</title>
        <subject>Devenez un backend hero avec Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://devfest.gdglille.org/#/schedule</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Kotlin gagne en popularité depuis la sortie officielle de sa version 1.0. Petit à petit, il devient la référence à la fois dans le monde du mobile (Android), du backend (Spring) et des outils (Gradle). Dans ce codelab nous allons introduire progressivement les concepts clé du langage à travers le développement du backend d'une application permettant de tester les capacités des développeurs, type CodinGame.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>it</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-30</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-30</endDate>
        <location>Pisa, Italy</location>
        <speaker>Gianni</speaker>
        <title>GDG Pisa</title>
        <subject>Merenda con Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GDG-Pisa/events/252067143/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Dopo KotlinLab, GDG Pisa propone di passare insieme un sabato pomeriggio alternativo presso il caffè letterario voltapagina, dove poter chiacchierare riguardo Kotlin tra una fetta di torta e l'altra. 🍰</p>
<p>L'evento è pensato per essere totalmente libero da schemi: potete fare domande riguardo quanto affrontato durante il KotlinLab o fare domande affini a Kotlin e al mondo che vi orbita (Android, Kotlin-native, librerie ecc).</p>
<p>Per partecipare non è necessaria alcuna propedeuticità, non è necessario portare un PC e non è necessario aver seguito il KotlinLab.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-30</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-30</endDate>
        <location>Gaborone, Botswana</location>
        <speaker>Kesego Tumisang</speaker>
        <title>GDG Gaborone</title>
        <subject>Kotlin for Beginners</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GDG-Gaborone/events/250956441/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-07-07</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-07-07</endDate>
        <location>Alexandria, Egypt</location>
        <speaker>Wessam Elsharawy</speaker>
        <title>GDG Alexandria</title>
        <subject>(Flutter - Angular - Kotlin) in parallel</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GDG-Alexandria/events/247743156/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-07-09</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-07-09</endDate>
        <location>Dublin, Ireland</location>
        <speaker>Tomás Hanley</speaker>
        <title>Dublin Kotlin Meetup</title>
        <subject>Intro to Kotlin &amp; starting the Kotlin Koans</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Dublin-Kotlin-Meetup/events/251790075/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>We'll be starting with a presentation on Kotlin, what it is, why you should use it, and why we're passionate about adopting it!</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-07-10</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-07-10</endDate>
        <location>Omaha, NE</location>
        <speaker>Parshav Chauhan</speaker>
        <title>Google Developer Group Omaha</title>
        <subject>Kotlin Λrrow</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GDGOmaha/events/251531835/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-18</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-18</endDate>
        <location>Richmond, VA</location>
        <speaker>Srki Rakic</speaker>
        <title>Richmond Java Users Group</title>
        <subject>Kotlin - What’s all the fuss about?</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Richmond-Java-Users-Group/events/249456585/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Kotlin is statically typed programming language that runs on JVM, now official programming language for Android development, and the most beloved language based on the StackOverflow.com. We’ll do an introduction to Kotlin, explore some of its basic features, and compare it to Java.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-18</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-18</endDate>
        <location>Chandler, AZ</location>
        <speaker>Matt C.</speaker>
        <title>Phoenix Software Engineering Reading Group</title>
        <subject>Kotlin in Action: Chapter 11 (DSL construction)</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Phoenix-Software-Engineering-Reading-Group/events/248982165/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-06</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-06</endDate>
        <location>Utrecht, Netherlands</location>
        <speaker>Vince Treur, Rene de Groot</speaker>
        <title>The Dutch Android User Group</title>
        <subject>Kotlin workshop</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/dutch-aug/events/249146731/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Join us for a meetup full of Kotlin. If you haven’t had the chance to get started with Kotlin this is the meetup for you. Vince Treur and Rene de Groot will guide you through the language to get you up and running in no time. Even though this is a workshop for beginners, people from all skill levels are more than welcome to join!</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-19</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-19</endDate>
        <location>Chicago, USA</location>
        <speaker>Thomas Nield</speaker>
        <title>Chicago Kotlin Users Group</title>
        <subject>Data Science with Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Chicago-Kotlin/events/248191902/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>We will be collaborating with the Chicago Java User Group for the first time to bring you Thomas Nield, one of the speakers from last year’s inaugural KotlinConf in San Francisco. He will be presenting on how Kotlin can help position the JVM as a data science platform with live code examples of libraries and techniques for areas like discrete optimization, Bayesian analysis and linear/nonlinear regression.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-19</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-19</endDate>
        <location>Lehi, UT, USA</location>
        <speaker>Matt Berteaux</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin Utah</title>
        <subject>Kotlin Meetup</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Kotlin-Utah/events/248803325/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Deep-dive on functions. Named parameters, extension functions, default parameters...we might even get real crazy and talk about lambdas!</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>de</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-19</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-19</endDate>
        <location>Berlin, Germany</location>
        <speaker>Javad Sadeqzadeh</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin user group Berlin</title>
        <subject>Kotlin at Blacklane</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/kotlin-berlin/events/246647207/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>de</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-19</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-19</endDate>
        <location>Berlin, Germany</location>
        <speaker>Kathleen Sharp</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin user group Berlin</title>
        <subject>The “state of Kotlin” survey results</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/kotlin-berlin/events/246647207/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>de</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-19</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-19</endDate>
        <location>Berlin, Germany</location>
        <speaker>Yan Braslavskiy</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin user group Berlin</title>
        <subject>The Ups &amp; Downs of Adopting Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/kotlin-berlin/events/246647207/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>de</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-19</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-19</endDate>
        <location>Berlin, Germany</location>
        <speaker>Nikita Belokopytov</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin user group Berlin</title>
        <subject>Kotlin and FLUXible MVVM</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/kotlin-berlin/events/246647207/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-20</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-20</endDate>
        <location>Kampala, Uganda</location>
        <speaker>Kevin Janvier</speaker>
        <title>GDG Kampala</title>
        <subject>Kotlin Beyond Android - Using Kotlin on New and Existing Projects</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GDG-Kampala/events/249864608/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Learn to code in Kotlin in a very pragmatic way, while going through code examples. Join us on Friday 20th April at Outbox technology hub from 5:00 PM to 8:00 PM. We shall use app examples to practice and get comfortable using Kotlin in Android development. 1 hour to review the Kotlin fundamentals, and 1 hours to use Kotlin for Android development.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-19</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-19</endDate>
        <location>Leeds, United Kingdom</location>
        <speaker>Alex Stanhope</speaker>
        <title>The JVM Thing</title>
        <subject>JVM and serverless – Kotlin at Skybet scale</subject>
        <url>
            https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/the-jvm-thing-jvm-lightning-talks-from-market-leading-tech-companies-in-yorkshire-tickets-44222915932
        </url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-19</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-19</endDate>
        <location>Leeds, United Kingdom</location>
        <speaker>James Morris</speaker>
        <title>The JVM Thing</title>
        <subject>Getting functional with Kotlin</subject>
        <url>
            https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/the-jvm-thing-jvm-lightning-talks-from-market-leading-tech-companies-in-yorkshire-tickets-44222915932
        </url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-19</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-19</endDate>
        <location>Leeds, United Kingdom</location>
        <speaker>Jaime Bowden</speaker>
        <title>The JVM Thing</title>
        <subject>Android from Java to Kotlin – An unexpected journey</subject>
        <url>
            https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/the-jvm-thing-jvm-lightning-talks-from-market-leading-tech-companies-in-yorkshire-tickets-44222915932
        </url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>de</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-25</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-25</endDate>
        <location>Görlitz, Germany</location>
        <speaker>Tobias Blaschke</speaker>
        <title>Java User Group Görlitz</title>
        <subject>Kotlin</subject>
        <url>http://www.jug-gr.de/2018/04/25/kotlin.html</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Die Ankündigung der Unterstützung von Kotlin für die Android-Entwicklung auf der Google I/O Keynote 2017 bewirkte spontan kräftigen Applaus. Kotlin ist nur eine weitere Programmiersprache für die JVM. Warum also bewirkt die verhältnismäßig dröge Ankündigung zur Unterstützung einer JVM-Sprache solche Begeisterung? Was ist das Besondere an Kotlin gegenüber Java? Der Vortrag gibt einen ersten allgemeinen Einblick in die Sprachfeatures von Kotlin und gibt Kotlin-Neulingen die Möglichkeit, sich selbst einen Eindruck über die Sprache zu verschaffen.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-25</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-25</endDate>
        <location>Richmond, VA</location>
        <speaker>Srki Rakic</speaker>
        <title>Richmond Java Users Group</title>
        <subject>Kotlin - What’s all the fuss about?</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Richmond-Java-Users-Group/events/249456585/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Kotlin is statically typed programming language that runs on JVM, now official programming language for Android development, and the most beloved language based on the StackOverflow.com. We’ll do an introduction to Kotlin, explore some of its basic features, and compare it to Java.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>ja</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-15</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-15</endDate>
        <location>Tokyo, Japan</location>
        <speaker>Hiromitsu Shinohara</speaker>
        <title>日本Kotlinユーザグループ</title>
        <subject>Kotlin初心者向けハンズオン #3 / Kotlin Hands-on for Beginners</subject>
        <url>https://kotlin.connpass.com/event/79344/</url>
        <content>
            <slides>https://speakerdeck.com/shanonim/kotlin-hands-on-for-beginners</slides>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Kotlin is statically typed programming language that runs on JVM, now official programming language for Android development, and the most beloved language based on the StackOverflow.com. We’ll do an introduction to Kotlin, explore some of its basic features, and compare it to Java.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-16</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-16</endDate>
        <location>Lugano, Switzerland</location>
        <speaker>Danny Preussler</speaker>
        <title>APP BUILDERS SWITZERLAND 2018</title>
        <subject>To Inject or not inject, Dependency Injection in a Kotlin world</subject>
        <url>https://appbuilders.ch/index.html</url>
        <content>
            <slides>
                https://speakerdeck.com/dpreussler/to-inject-or-not-inject-dependency-injection-in-a-kotlin-world-appbuilders-dot-ch-2018
            </slides>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Dependency Injection via frameworks like Dagger were present in most modern Android projects. But then Kotlin happened. And since then a bunch of new libraries like Koin or Kodein appeared. Developers are even writing articles how to do DI without any framework. Some argue that those don’t even offer real dependency injection. Let’s look at that argument and compare the approaches. So, is there something wrong with Dagger & co. in Kotlin? Are they obsolete? What are the alternatives? Let’s dive in.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-30</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-30</endDate>
        <location>Lahore, Pakistan</location>
        <speaker>Mehmood Asghar</speaker>
        <title>ioScrum</title>
        <subject>What's new in kotlin?</subject>
        <url>https://www.ioscrum.com/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Just developed an app in android.Want to convert it in kotlin.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>it</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-20</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-20</endDate>
        <location>Turin, Italy</location>
        <speaker>Lorenzo Quiroli</speaker>
        <title>droidcon Italy</title>
        <subject>Kotlin Tips &amp; Tricks</subject>
        <url>http://it.droidcon.com/2018/agenda/</url>
        <content>
            <slides>https://speakerdeck.com/quiro91/kotlin-tips-and-tricks</slides>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-20</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-20</endDate>
        <location>Turin, Italy</location>
        <speaker>Marcin Moskała</speaker>
        <title>droidcon italy</title>
        <subject>Multiplatform Kotlin Development</subject>
        <url>http://it.droidcon.com/2018/agenda/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>it</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-20</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-20</endDate>
        <location>Turin, Italy</location>
        <speaker>Fabio Collini</speaker>
        <title>droidcon italy</title>
        <subject>From Java to Kotlin beyond Alt+Shift+Cmd+K</subject>
        <url>http://it.droidcon.com/2018/agenda/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-20</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-20</endDate>
        <location>Turin, Italy</location>
        <speaker>Erik Hellman</speaker>
        <title>droidcon italy</title>
        <subject>Better asynchronous programming with Kotlin Coroutines</subject>
        <url>http://it.droidcon.com/2018/agenda/</url>
        <content>
            <slides>https://speakerdeck.com/erikhellman/better-async-with-kotlin-coroutines</slides>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-20</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-20</endDate>
        <location>Turin, Italy</location>
        <speaker>Stefan May</speaker>
        <title>droidcon italy</title>
        <subject>How to write Gradle plugins (in Kotlin)</subject>
        <url>http://it.droidcon.com/2018/agenda/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-23</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-23</endDate>
        <location>Paris, France</location>
        <speaker>Amal Kakaiya</speaker>
        <title>Android Makers Paris| 2018</title>
        <subject>Travelling across Asia - Our journey from Java to Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://androidmakers.fr/schedule/#session-58</url>
        <content>
            <video>https://www.youtube.com/watch?list=PLn7H9CUCuXAus0YgFW7QiIpnwHJd3Yinw&amp;time_continue=6&amp;v=ZaPIcI42Qtw
            </video>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Kotlin brought new excitement to Android development, but the thought of converting a Java codebase to Kotlin can be quite daunting. Where do you start? What problems will you run into? How long will it take?</p>
<p>Deliveroo’s journey to Kotlin started over a year ago. This session will take you through their journey, the issues they’ve faced and how Kotlin can improve your codebase, your app and your sanity.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-23</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-23</endDate>
        <location>Paris, France</location>
        <speaker>Erik Hellman</speaker>
        <title>Android Makers Paris| 2018</title>
        <subject>Better asynchronous programming with Kotlin Coroutines</subject>
        <url>https://androidmakers.fr/schedule/#session-14</url>
        <content>
            <video>
                https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Bb4CVrf5al4&amp;index=11&amp;list=PLn7H9CUCuXAus0YgFW7QiIpnwHJd3Yinw
            </video>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Android application development is inherently asynchronous. Even the simplest Android application requires the developer to track asynchronous callbacks of the activity, often leading to the infamous callback hell. In this talk, we will have a look at the latest addition to the solutions for dealing with asynchronous programming on Android; Kotlin Coroutines. We'll learn about what coroutines are, how they differ from other models and how to use it with Kotlin on Android.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-23</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-23</endDate>
        <location>Paris, France</location>
        <speaker>Alexander Gherschon</speaker>
        <title>Android Makers Paris| 2018</title>
        <subject>Kotlinify your Gradle</subject>
        <url>https://androidmakers.fr/schedule/#session-45</url>
        <content>
            <slides>https://speakerdeck.com/alexgherschon/kotlinify-your-gradle</slides>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>The Gradle build tool is based on the JVM, so where does Kotlin fit in that ecosystem? We will see how Kotlin finds its place in that world, would it be by extending Gradle or by using Gradle Plugins with Kotlin.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-23</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-23</endDate>
        <location>Paris, France</location>
        <speaker>Mitchell Tilbrook</speaker>
        <title>Android Makers Paris| 2018</title>
        <subject>Kotlin Backstage</subject>
        <url>https://androidmakers.fr/schedule/#session-61</url>
        <content>
            <slides>https://www.slideshare.net/vonGraham/kotlin-backstage-android-makers-paris-2018</slides>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Kotlin offers a modern language design in contrast to Java, while at the same time maintaining full Java interoperably: Data classes, properties, delegation, inline functions, string interpolation and much more. But, if Java can't offer these features how come Kotlin can? What does Kotlin do to make it possible to use this Syntactic sugar?</p>
<p>In this talk, we will go backstage and dig into the Bytecode that Kotlin generates to make all the features we love work on a runtime that technically does not support them. We will look at the impact kotlin code generations has on method count. Get a deeper understanding of how Object and companion object work and see the implications of the use of either under different circumstances. Finally look at common patterns that can help reduce the size of both the bytecode and method count.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-23</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-23</endDate>
        <location>Paris, France</location>
        <speaker>Simone Civetta</speaker>
        <title>Android Makers Paris| 2018</title>
        <subject>Reusable Cross-Platform Frameworks with Kotlin/Native</subject>
        <url>https://androidmakers.fr/schedule/#session-42</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>While building entire cross-platform apps might often turn out to be a bad idea, mission-critical client-specific logic can greatly benefit from an unique codebase, allowing code to be written - and tested - once. Since end 2016, Kotlin/Native can compile Kotlin code to a binary form, which can be embedded into a native app. In this talk you will learn why it makes sense, and how, to leverage these experimental features and build a cross-platform module reusable on both Android and iOS.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-23</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-23</endDate>
        <location>Paris, France</location>
        <speaker>Wolfram Rittmeyer</speaker>
        <title>Android Makers Paris| 2018</title>
        <subject>Kotlin DSLs</subject>
        <url>https://androidmakers.fr/schedule/#session-66</url>
        <content>
            <slides>https://speakerdeck.com/writtmeyer/kotlin-dsls</slides>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Kotlin is not just about null safety or data classes. Kotlin has much more to offer. One of the nice things is the ability to use Kotlin's features to create domain specific languages (DSLs).</p>
<p>In this talk you will see samples of DSLs you can use in your Android projects and learn how they work.</p>
<p>Kotlin DSLs are actually made of many simple Kotlin features - some of which you surely already use, some of which are a bit more obscure. But combined together they give us a powerful way to create nice DSLs.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-23</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-23</endDate>
        <location>Paris, France</location>
        <speaker>Kirill Suslov</speaker>
        <title>Android Makers Paris| 2018</title>
        <subject>Explore Kotlin.Collections API</subject>
        <url>https://androidmakers.fr/schedule/#session-66</url>
        <content>
            <slides>https://speakerdeck.com/kirill_suslov/explore-kotlin-dot-collections-api</slides>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Kotlin is out here for a while now but many developers don’t use full power of it and write Java-style of Kotlin. let and apply are the only language features get adopted. This talk is aimed to overcome a small learning curve in one very common thing developers work every day with: collections. Backed by familiar Java collection API but supplemented by a set of handy functions, Kotlin collection API becomes a versatile tool that helps to develop faster and makes code clearer and nicer.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-23</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-23</endDate>
        <location>Paris, France</location>
        <speaker>Christophe Beyls</speaker>
        <title>Android Makers Paris| 2018</title>
        <subject>Kotlin's hidden costs, revisited</subject>
        <url>https://androidmakers.fr/schedule/#session-76</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Kotlin has become the default modern programming language for many Android developers, with first-class support in Android Studio. But exactly how much performance and code size are we sacrificing for making use of all the additional features this language provides compared to Java?</p>
<p>We'll study the Java bytecode generated by the Kotlin compiler in various scenarios in order to find out which code constructs come with hidden performance penalties and learn how to become better Kotlin programmers. Some significant improvements in the recent versions of Kotlin will also be highlighted.</p>
<p>This talk is based on the series of blog posts from the speaker and extends it in some areas.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>ru</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-20</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-20</endDate>
        <location>St.Petersburg, Russia</location>
        <speaker>Roman Yatsyna, Ivan Vazhnov</speaker>
        <title>Mobius</title>
        <subject>Мультиплатформенная архитектура на Kotlin для iOS и Android</subject>
        <url>https://mobiusconf.com/2018/spb/talks/5scrjaz2ieoyw2ikwwawek/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Kotlin семимильными шагами двигается в сторону кроссплатформенности, появляются десятки репозиториев с приложениями различной сложности.</p>
<p>Мы расскажем как уже сейчас начать скрещивать Clean Architecture с Kotlin Multiplatform Projects, как писать бизнес-логику приложения один раз для всех платформ и какие ограничения наложит такой подход.</p>
<p>Доклад будет интересен адептам Kotlin, которые не боятся приставок Experimental и бойлерплейта чистого архитектурного подхода.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>ru</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-20</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-20</endDate>
        <location>St.Petersburg, Russia</location>
        <speaker>Andrey Breslav</speaker>
        <title>Mobius</title>
        <subject>На плечах гигантов: языки, у которых учился Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://mobiusconf.com/2018/spb/talks/4br9b0dlvy28ig6eymyeei/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Расскажем о тех языках, из которых мы заимствовали идеи и концепции, когда разрабатывали Kotlin. В числе прочего, речь пойдет о Java, C#, Scala, Groovy, Python, Gosu и т.д. Покажем, как некоторые из этих идей изменились в нашей интерпретации. И немного расскажем о том, какие известные языки теперь учатся на нашем опыте (Swift, Java, Hack, C#).</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>ru</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-20</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-20</endDate>
        <location>St.Petersburg, Russia</location>
        <speaker>Vladimir Ivanov</speaker>
        <title>Mobius</title>
        <subject>Скрипач не нужен: отказываемся от RxJava в пользу корутин в Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://mobiusconf.com/2018/spb/talks/mt2eecqokiosqguiooouu/</url>
        <content>
            <slides>https://drive.google.com/file/d/1X8WvNvdfR6pJgVLvhXP_JH_-Qdbdv3U-/view</slides>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>65% разработчиков, начиная проект на Kotlin, выбирают RxJava 2 в качестве инструмента для фоновой работы. Но насколько оправдан этот выбор? Корутины в Kotlin могут стать мощной заменой RxJava. В докладе мы сравним оба подхода, рассмотрим их плюсы и минусы, посмотрим, в каких случаях удобнее использовать корутины, а в каких не обойтись без Rx. Увидим, как тестировать код, написанный с помощью обоих подходов и насколько они могут сосуществовать.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-24</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-24</endDate>
        <location>Amersfoort, Netherlands</location>
        <speaker>Paulien van Alst</speaker>
        <title>OpenValue</title>
        <subject>Hands on Kotlin workshop</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/OpenValue/events/248951751/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Kotlin is the new JVM language where all the best practices of programming come together. Looking forward to discover a language that will support you in writing readable and understandable code in the fewest lines possible? Without any help of any extra libraries such as Lombok, Guava and even more, Kotlin will challenge you to write code that even the business analyst should be able to understand. With Kotlin you can finally focus on the business features you want to implement instead working on the language itself. In this workshop, you will build a simple webservice in Kotlin and hopefully see how easy it can be to write new business functionality.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-24</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-24</endDate>
        <location>Columbus, OH</location>
        <speaker>David Lucas</speaker>
        <title>Columbus Kotlin User Group</title>
        <subject>fun Unit Testing with Baco</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Columbus-Kotlin-User-Group/events/249504592/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Join us as we review some of the current frameworks available for unit testing Kotlin including kotlin.test, JUnit 5, and Spek (yes, in Dutch it means Bacon). Examples will be provided for Kotlin JVM, Kotlin JS, and Kotlin Native.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>ro</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-24</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-24</endDate>
        <location>Bucharest, Romania</location>
        <speaker>Gabi Bornea</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin User Group Bucharest</title>
        <subject>Kotlin Explained Series - Functional Programming</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/kug-bucharest/events/248498109/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Kotlin its a strong type programming language which embraces both Functional and Object Oriented paradigms.
This brings the power of the two "worlds" -> functional programming in the small and object oriented programming in the large.</p>
<p>In this first part of the series we are going to see how Kotlin (and arrow) embraces the functional programming paradigm to lead to more maintainable, easy to reason, succinct yet expressive and concurrent friendly applications.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-25</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-25</endDate>
        <location>London, UK</location>
        <speaker>Andrea Bresolin</speaker>
        <title>GDG London</title>
        <subject>Kotlin Coroutines: make your world more synchronous</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/gdglondon/events/249120389/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>In this talk we’ll have an introduction to the coroutines in Kotlin. We’ll see how they work, what we can do with them and how they can help us in making our code look more synchronous and easier to manage. We’ll also briefly discuss about the interaction with existing code and we’ll take a look at some of the “crazy” things that such a powerful tool allows us to do. The talk will be mainly focused on Android, but many of the concepts could probably be useful also in other platforms where Kotlin coroutines are available.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-25</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-25</endDate>
        <location>London, UK</location>
        <speaker>Zan Markan</speaker>
        <title>GDG London</title>
        <subject>The State of Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/gdglondon/events/249120389/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Over the last three months I ran a survey of the global Kotlin ecosystem. My goal was to learn how developers use and adopt Kotlin - either in work or side projects, or just for playing around, and what are some of the most popular resources for learning it.</p>
<p>The survey was a great success, and gained over 2400 responses in total! The results are meant to become a resource for the Kotlin community. Something we can all look at for interesting insights that will also help drive adoption of Kotlin in our teams and organisations.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>de</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-25</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-25</endDate>
        <location>Berlin, Germany</location>
        <speaker>Mohsen Mirhoseini</speaker>
        <title>GDG Berlin Android</title>
        <subject>Using Protobuf in Android apps plus extra Kotlin flavor</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GDG-Berlin-Android/events/247340319/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Protocol Buffers is a method of serializing structured data developed by Google for internal usage which also provided a code generator for multiple languages. In this talk I am going to talk about serializing structured data as shrink as possible using Google Protobuf inside your Android app and a fast comparison between this protocol and JSON.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>es</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-26</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-26</endDate>
        <location>Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic</location>
        <speaker>Noe Branagan</speaker>
        <title>GDG Santo Domingo</title>
        <subject>Kotlin 001</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GDG-Santo-Domingo/events/249902621/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Finalmente tendremos regularmente actividades de kotlin, estaremos actualizando mas informaciones sobre este primera reunión.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-26</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-26</endDate>
        <location>Dallas, TX</location>
        <speaker>Edgar Tremillo</speaker>
        <title>Tech Talent South - Dallas</title>
        <subject>Learn basic Android and Kotlin Programming</subject>
        <url>https://www.eventbrite.com/e/learn-basic-android-and-kotlin-programming-tickets-45145894586</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Learn basic Android and Kotlin programming. Friend to TTS, Edgar Tremillo, will cover some basic concepts such as Android application components, structure, layout, the Kotlin syntax and main advantages over Java. This meetup is suitable for anyone with little to no knowledge of Android or Kotlin programming.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>fr</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-26</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-26</endDate>
        <location>Nantes, France</location>
        <speaker>Yvelain Naude</speaker>
        <title>Nantes Java User Group</title>
        <subject>À la découverte de Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Nantes-Java-User-Group/events/249153190/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Kotlin est un langage de programmation qui s’adresse principalement aux utilisateurs Java. Supporté depuis l’année dernière par les plateformes Android, ce langage simple et moderne a fait une percée dans le monde du développement mobile. Interopérable avec Java, Kotlin est désormais doté d’une version JS et native qui élargit le champ de ses capacités.</p>
<p>Après un vernis historique sur les origines de ce langage, découvrons ensemble tout l’intérêt de Kotlin au travers de quelques points de syntaxe, concepts de base et outils. Nous terminerons ce talk par la présentation de deux exemples l’un sur Android et l’autre en Kotlin JS.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>pt</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-27</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-27</endDate>
        <location>Cascavel,Brasil</location>
        <speaker>Wellington Mitrut</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin Night Cascavel 2018 #1</title>
        <subject>Lottie + Kotlin = ❤</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Kotlin-Meetup-Cascavel/events/249548017/</url>
        <content>
            <slides>https://speakerdeck.com/wmitrut/lottie-plus-kotlin-equals-3</slides>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-28</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-28</endDate>
        <location>Kirkland, WA</location>
        <speaker>Clare</speaker>
        <title>Eastside Android Development Meetup</title>
        <subject>Discuss about Kotlin.</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Eastside-Android-Development-Meetup/events/249647692/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>We are just going to discuss about Android Kotlin this time. A lot of us use Java in Android studio. Since Kotlin is now an official language on Android, we would love to know more about it too. We all can do a quick research and share what you learned about Kotlin.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-28</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-28</endDate>
        <location>Vanderbijlpark, South Africa</location>
        <speaker>Kanyinda Kalonji</speaker>
        <title>GDG VUT</title>
        <subject>Let's Code Android App In Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GDG-VUT/events/246480330/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-28</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-28</endDate>
        <location>Chennai, India</location>
        <speaker>Hadi Hariri</speaker>
        <title>JetBrains Day Chennai</title>
        <subject>Kotlin: Beyond Android Development</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/JetBrains-Day-Chennai/events/249156446/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>This talk is about covering the language aspects that you usually don’t see in a 101 talk. Topics include amongst other:</p>
<p>-Generics and how Kotlin handles Covariance and Contravariance</p>
<p>-The secrets of inline functions in Kotlin</p>
<p>-Reified generics and avoiding type erasure on the JVM</p>
<p>-Lazy evaluation with sequences</p>
<p>-Using delegation to leverage code reuse</p>
<p>-Object invocations and lambdas with receivers for better DSL’s</p>
<p>-A view of asynchronous programming with coroutines</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-01</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-01</endDate>
        <location>Cork, Ireland</location>
        <speaker>Garth Gilmour</speaker>
        <title>Cork Java User Group</title>
        <subject>Using Arrow Library in Kotlin, with Garth Gilmour</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/corkjug/events/248500745/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-05</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-05</endDate>
        <location>Jalandhar, India</location>
        <speaker>Karan Verma</speaker>
        <title>Jalandhar Kotlin Meetup</title>
        <subject>Getting started with Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://nvite.com/JalandharKotlin/13lv7v</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Overview of Kotlin</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-21</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-21</endDate>
        <location>Bangalore, India</location>
        <speaker>Jitin Sharma</speaker>
        <title>BlrDroid - Bangalore Android Developers Group</title>
        <subject>Migration production android app from Java to Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/blrdroid/events/249149873/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Through the talk I'll be discussing about how we introduced kotlin in a live project and made it work with existing java files. I'll also talk about various problems faced at project level and how we resolved them.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-21</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-21</endDate>
        <location>Hyderabad, Indian</location>
        <speaker>Pankaj Rai</speaker>
        <title>Hyderabad Mobile &amp; Emerging Tech Group</title>
        <subject>Kotlin hands-on for Android</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/blrdroid/events/249149873/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>A demonstration of how to write production quality app using kotlin. Why kotlin is important for android app developer, it's usage and features also having a coding session for developers to gain confidence over building apps using kotlin.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-28</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-28</endDate>
        <location>Delhi, India</location>
        <speaker>Ashish Krishnan</speaker>
        <title>Delhi-NCR Java User Group</title>
        <subject>Dive into Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Delhi-NCR-JUG/events/245487971/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Kotlin as a language has a lot of similarities to Java in structure — it's object-oriented, concise, type-safe, and designed for similar problems that Java solves with fewer NPEs. It is interoperable with Java, it brings in nice-to-have features out-of-box over Java with a functional programming flavor. It opens doors for other Java-like frameworks on the server, mobile, and browsers. In this session of 45 minutes, we dive into the basics of Kotlin and its features, comparison to Java and slowly understand the idea of mutual co-existence.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>ja</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-24</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-24</endDate>
        <location>Tokyo, Japan</location>
        <speaker>Satoru Fujiwara</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin Android APP DOJO</title>
        <subject>KotlinによるAndroidアプリ開発の最新情報</subject>
        <url>https://events.withgoogle.com/app-dojo-april-2018-2nd/</url>
        <content>
            <slides>https://speakerdeck.com/satorufujiwara/kotlin-android-app-dojo</slides>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>uk</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-17</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-17</endDate>
        <location>Kiev, Ukraine</location>
        <speaker>Dmitry Jemerov</speaker>
        <title>Rockstar Night</title>
        <subject>Multiplatform development with Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.facebook.com/events/166486264049260</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>AIn Kotlin 1.2, we’ve added support for developing multiplatform projects. Multiplatform projects allow you to reuse the business logic written in Kotlin between all the components of your application — backend code on the JVM, frontend code in JS, and also mobile apps. The common code is compiled for all platforms and can access platform-specific implementations of APIs and libraries. The platform-specific parts are also written in Kotlin and have access to the full set of features of the corresponding platform.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>ru</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-06</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-06</endDate>
        <location>Moscow, Russia</location>
        <speaker>Dmitry Zhemerov</speaker>
        <title>JPoint 2018</title>
        <subject>Идиоматичный Kotlin: от форматирования до DSL</subject>
        <url>https://jpoint.ru/talks/3hvhevcj2uwuums0umayam/</url>
        <content>
            <slides>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2raT3QX3aNg&amp;feature=youtu.be</slides>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Начать пользоваться Kotlin несложно — он похож на Java, и ваш существующий опыт легко позволит вам начать программировать в стиле Java. В этом докладе вы узнаете о возможностях языка и стандартной библиотеки Kotlin, которые позволят вам выйти на следующий уровень и писать по-настоящему компактный и выразительный код. Сочетание этих возможностей позволяет строить на базе Kotlin так называемые «доменно-ориентированные языки», которые позволяют декларативно выражать сложные наборы инструкций. Мы рассмотрим несколько примеров таких языков и то, как вы сможете сами создавать их.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-04</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-04</endDate>
        <location>Bern,Switzerland</location>
        <speaker>Martin Kräuchi</speaker>
        <title>Bern Hack Night</title>
        <subject>Kotlin Hacking Night</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Bern-Hack-Night/events/249361513/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>For all Kotlin beginners and already experienced user: After an introduction to the JVM language Kotlin we will work together on projects to create some meaningful functionalities in Kotlin, like some kind of web services or IoT integration.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-02</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-02</endDate>
        <location>Johannesburg, South Africa</location>
        <speaker>Christoff Smith</speaker>
        <title>Jozi Java User Group</title>
        <subject>You want to put Kotlin where?</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Jozi-JUG/events/249575133/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-02</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-02</endDate>
        <location>New York, NY, USA</location>
        <speaker>Izzy Oji, Lisa Luo</speaker>
        <title>Brooklyn Kotlin</title>
        <subject>Casual Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Brooklyn-Kotlin/events/249353536/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>how to dip your toes in Kotlin on Android and leverage the language's niceties without the daunt of converting your whole app</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-02</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-02</endDate>
        <location>New York, NY, USA</location>
        <speaker>Kevin Galligan</speaker>
        <title>Brooklyn Kotlin</title>
        <subject>Kotlin Mobile (Android &amp; IOS) Multiplatform Preview</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Brooklyn-Kotlin/events/249353536/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>The Kotlin/Native side of Multiplatform was discussed a lot after KotlinConf, but not a lot has been built. That will be changing over the next few months. We'll go over some of the libraries coming soon, demo SqlLite and some other architectural libraries on iOS, and walk through the pieces needed to get started</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>es</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-02</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-02</endDate>
        <location>Barcelona, Spain</location>
        <speaker>Jorge Garrido</speaker>
        <title>Barcelona Android Developer Group</title>
        <subject>Creating Kotlin DSLs on Android</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Barcelona-Android-Developer-Group/events/249934143/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>In this meetup we will learn to create our own DSL in Kotlin, we will see examples and we will combine them with extension functions to achieve a more readable code, easy to extend and modify.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>tr</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-02</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-02</endDate>
        <location>Istanbul, Turkey</location>
        <speaker>Murat Can Bur</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin Istanbul</title>
        <subject>A summary of Kotlin tips from #31DaysofKotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Kotlin-%C4%B0stanbul/events/249968961/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>İkinci etkinliğimizde Murat Can Bur, A summary of Kotlin tips from #31DaysofKotlin sunumu ile bizlerle olacak.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>es</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-02</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-02</endDate>
        <location>Guadalajara, Mexico</location>
        <speaker>Sinuhe Jaime</speaker>
        <title>GDG Guadalajara Android</title>
        <subject>Introduction to Koin, the DI for lazy people</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GDG-GDL-Android/events/250147326/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>We are used to Dagger and it works great along with android because of the compiler. But what if we are running on Kotlin? Dagger can integrate using some changes on the project, but still has Java in the way. What if we want something more… functional? Koin is a DI tool to manage our DI flow using only FP and can lead you to awesome results.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>es</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-03</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-03</endDate>
        <location>La Paz, Bolivia</location>
        <speaker>Brayan Mamani Mamani</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin El Alto</title>
        <subject>Fundamentos de Kotlin: Conclusiones</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Kotlin-El-Alto/events/249062565/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-03</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-03</endDate>
        <location>Tel Aviv-Yafo, Israel</location>
        <speaker>Boris Farber</speaker>
        <title>KotlinTLV</title>
        <subject>Improve your Kotlin Android build with AS Poet</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/KotlinTLV/events/249859824/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-03</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-03</endDate>
        <location>Tel Aviv-Yafo, Israel</location>
        <speaker>Alexander Gherschon</speaker>
        <title>KotlinTLV</title>
        <subject>Kotlinify your Gradle</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/KotlinTLV/events/249859824/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-03</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-03</endDate>
        <location>Vilnus, Lithuania</location>
        <speaker>Alexander Podkhalyuzin</speaker>
        <title>Google Developer Group Vilnius</title>
        <subject>Kotlin.Native: cross platform Android/iOS development</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Google-Developer-Group-Vilnius/events/250040370/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Kotlin is going to be the standard language for Android. We already see lots of teams moving to this very promising language. But in JetBrains we just don't want to stop on that. So we are working on Kotlin.Native, the same language, different backend. And one of the most promising applications for this backend is iOS development.</p>
<p>In this talk I'll do short introduction into Kotlin language itself with description of some high level design ideas. Next step will be discussions around Native as a platform. I'll show you current complications with it and possible solutions. And finally we will go to iOS. You will see cross compiled Android/iOS example as well as example with just shared business logic. As a bonus I'll show you infinite possibilities about single language with all the parts, backend, frontend and two mobile apps.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>it</lang>
        <startDate>2018-08-25</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-08-25</endDate>
        <location>Levante, Italy</location>
        <speaker>Roberto Orgiu</speaker>
        <title>GDG DevFest Levante</title>
        <subject>Kotlin 101</subject>
        <url>http://devfestlevante.eu/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Benvenuti nell'universo Android! Roberto Orgiu, GDE Android ci introdurrà Kotlin il nuovo linguaggi di programmazione di IntelliJ e promosso come linguaggio principale su Android insieme a Java</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-08</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-08</endDate>
        <location>Oklahoma City, OK</location>
        <speaker>Jason Lee</speaker>
        <title>OKC JUG</title>
        <subject>Jerkey: An introduction to Kotlin DSLs using Jersey</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/okcjug/events/250327922/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>In this session, we'll start from the beginning as we build Jerkey, Kotlin-based DSL for building Jersey applications (Jersey + Kotlin = Jerkey ;). We'll start by covering the basics you need to understand in order write a DSL. Next, we'll spec out how we want the DSL to look and work, and, finally, we'll implement it and in doing so demonstrate not only the power of Kotlin, but how well the Kotlin/Java interop really is by showing code paths bouncing between Java and Kotlin code.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-08</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-08</endDate>
        <location>Montreal, Canada</location>
        <speaker>Vincent Carrier</speaker>
        <title>GDG Montreal Android</title>
        <subject>Writing a library in Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GDG-Montreal-Android/events/249035266/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Learn about the quirks of writing, benchmarking and publishing a library in Kotlin</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-08</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-08</endDate>
        <location>Kranj, Slovenia</location>
        <speaker>Rok Petek</speaker>
        <title>I/O Extended 2018 Kranj</title>
        <subject>Android developer at Toshl: Kotlin on Android and other platforms</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/I-O-Extended-2018-Kranj/events/249974113/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>We will dive into the not-so-new Kotlin language and explore its code sharing capabilities between different platforms.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-08</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-08</endDate>
        <location>Budapest, Hungary</location>
        <speaker>Márton Braun</speaker>
        <title>GDG Budapest</title>
        <subject>Top 10 Kotlin Stack Overflow questions</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GDG-Budapest/events/248277054/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>es</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-08</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-08</endDate>
        <location>Guadalajara, Mexico</location>
        <speaker>Ernesto Espinosa</speaker>
        <title>Guadalajara Kotlin User Group</title>
        <subject>Solving an Onsite Challenge with Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Kotlin-User-Group-GDL/events/250414448/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Aunque a veces lo olvidemos, una parte MUY importante de nuestro mundo son los Algoritmos. Kotlin da un agregado muy interesante al trabajar con colecciones de datos y puede ser de muchisima ayuda para lidiar con esos retos que se nos presentan en entrevistas de trabajo.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-08</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-08</endDate>
        <location>Bangalore, India</location>
        <speaker>Chandra Sekhar Nayak</speaker>
        <title>BlrKotlin - Kotlin User Group</title>
        <subject>Google I/O Extended 2018 (BlrKotlin + BlrDroid)</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/BlrKotlin/events/250336757/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-09</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-09</endDate>
        <location>Amsterdam, The Netherlands</location>
        <speaker>Joost Heijkoop</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin.amsterdam</title>
        <subject>Building a Spring app with Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/kotlin-amsterdam/events/250387904/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Time for our next meetup. Let's do something different. I like to do a walk-through, creating a web app back-end written in Kotlin using Spring! Let's see how Kotlin can help us in an environment we might be used to from Java-land.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>id</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-06</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-06</endDate>
        <location>Semarang, Indonesia</location>
        <speaker>Asif Hussain</speaker>
        <title>Android Kotlin Basic</title>
        <subject>Basic Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScpeI9-5GNB5SYvSSeXW6Zs0ANMspj_KNOb5-7qQVobpZgsMQ/viewform?c=0&amp;
            w=1
        </url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Workshop free untuk developer mobile yang mau terjun ke Kotlin</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>ru</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-18</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-18</endDate>
        <location>Kiev, Ukraine</location>
        <speaker>Marharyta Nedzelska</speaker>
        <title>Java Eastern Europe Conference 2018</title>
        <subject>Kotlin: lazy language for lazy people</subject>
        <url>https://jeeconf.com/program/kotlin-lazy-language-for-lazy-people/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>A few years ago you had to work hard to succeed in some fields. Nowadays you don’t need to work hard but to work smart. So this means that most of the time laziness (of course not extremely) is useful for our productivity. On the other hand, laziness is extremely important when you work with large amount of data and reduced space or power. In this talk we will try to cover all aspects of laziness in Kotlin: starting from lazy initialization of properties using delegates, lazy collections, sequences and, finally, laziness with coroutines. The main thing we would like to talk about is how to use this laziness and be productive with it. To see one more benefit of laziness in Kotlin we’ll refactor a real application to use lazy calculations.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>ru</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-18</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-18</endDate>
        <location>Kiev, Ukraine</location>
        <speaker>Dmitry Jemerov</speaker>
        <title>Java Eastern Europe Conference 2018</title>
        <subject>Kotlin: new silver bullet or the future</subject>
        <url>https://jeeconf.com/program/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>ru</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-18</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-18</endDate>
        <location>Kiev, Ukraine</location>
        <speaker>Dmitry Jemerov</speaker>
        <title>Java Eastern Europe Conference 2018</title>
        <subject>Developing multiplatform projects in Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://jeeconf.com/program/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p> Kotlin 1.2, we’ve added support for developing multiplatform projects. Multiplatform projects allow you to reuse the business logic written in Kotlin between all the components of your application – backend code on the JVM, frontend code in JS, and also mobile apps. The common code is compiled for all platforms and can access platform-specific implementations of APIs and libraries. The platform-specific parts are also written in Kotlin and have access to the full set of features of the corresponding platform.</p>
<p>In this talk, we’ll look at language and IDE features that support developing multiplatform projects, and at the libraries that can be used in such projects. As an example, we’ll study a project that supports isomorphic HTML rendering, or, in other words, reuses the HTML building code between the frontend and the backend.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>ru</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-18</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-18</endDate>
        <location>Kiev, Ukraine</location>
        <speaker>Ruslan Klymenko</speaker>
        <title>Java Eastern Europe Conference 2018</title>
        <subject>Kotlin decompiled. The closer look to comparision between java and kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://jeeconf.com/program/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>The talk is about Kotlin features, which are decompiled to Java code. You’ll understand how all of this ‘magic’ works in depths, which benefits it’ll give to you and what you may loose. Some benchmarks are included as a bonus.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>ru</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-18</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-18</endDate>
        <location>Kiev, Ukraine</location>
        <speaker>Aleksandr Tarasov</speaker>
        <title>Java Eastern Europe Conference 2018</title>
        <subject>Automating experiments with Kotlin DSL</subject>
        <url>https://jeeconf.com/program/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>In a large project, you can not just take it and make it available to all customers. Therefore, experiments are conducted that require manual changes that lead to time costs and sometimes errors. To remove these factors, Odnoklassniki decided to automate the preparation and launch of experiments. In the report, Aleksandr Tarasov will tell you why Kotlin was chosen for this, rather than the classic configuration management tools (such as Ansible), why a good DSL and toolkit are critical to this task. Make a deep dive into Kotlin Script feature and overcome problems that we’ve solved in order for everything to work as originally conceived.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>ru</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-18</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-18</endDate>
        <location>Kiev, Ukraine</location>
        <speaker>Izzet Mustafaiev</speaker>
        <title>Java Eastern Europe Conference 2018</title>
        <subject>Kotlin strives for Deep Learning</subject>
        <url>https://jeeconf.com/program/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>AI is New Electricity and Deep Learning is one of key enablers for this, it breaks known limits of possible and disrupts vast areas of our modern life. From dev standpoint it sounds science-heavy and requires PhD in fact its not. Here I’m going to explain why in theory and practice with Kotlin. Kotlin is a modern language with great perspectives to write concise, safe and interoperable applications, while Deep Learning is something what we’re going to develop in the nearest future. So why not to combine those 2 powers into 1?</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-12</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-12</endDate>
        <location>Mumbai, India</location>
        <speaker>Jayesh Solanki</speaker>
        <title>GDG Mumbai</title>
        <subject>Kotlin Codelab</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GDG-Mumbai/events/250506650/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-14</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-14</endDate>
        <location>Tel Aviv-Yafo, Israel</location>
        <speaker>Haim Michael</speaker>
        <title>life michael meetups</title>
        <subject>Kotlin Crash Course</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/life-michael/events/243709706/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-09</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-10</endDate>
        <location>San Francisco, CA, USA</location>
        <speaker>Seetha Annamraju</speaker>
        <title>Velos Weekend of Kotlin 2018</title>
        <subject>Workshop</subject>
        <url>https://www.eventbrite.com/e/velos-weekend-of-kotlin-2018-tickets-45906904788</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Kotlin is now an officially supported language for Android development!</p>
<p>So if you’re an Android developer thinking of transitioning to Kotlin, or just want to see if Kotlin is right for your team, this workshop is for you! Over two days, we will cover basic Kotlin syntax, conventions, good practices, and move on to build a working Android app. By the end of the workshop, you will walk away with a solid understanding of the benefits of Kotlin, and the ability to start thinking in Kotlin for Android development.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-13</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-13</endDate>
        <location>Olomouc, Czech Republic</location>
        <speaker>Lukáš Novák</speaker>
        <title>GDG Olomouc</title>
        <subject>Kotlin vs. Java</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GDG-Olomouc/events/250713355/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>At the next GDG Olomouc event, we look at the world of Java and their related languages. For the balanced content of the lecture we invited two specialists this time. The first will introduce us to the Kotlin language and the reasons for programming in Kotlin instead of Java. The other holds the view that old good Java has something in its own right. 3 ... 2 ... 1 ... FIGHT!</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>fr</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-29</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-29</endDate>
        <location>Montpellier, France</location>
        <speaker>Alexandre Delattre</speaker>
        <title>Sunny Tech 2018</title>
        <subject>Kotlin by Example</subject>
        <url>https://sunny-tech.io/schedule/day2?sessionId=3807</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>En annonçant le support officiel de Kotlin pour Android lors de la dernière Google I/O, Google a donné un énorme élan à ce superbe langage. Ce n'est pas si surprenant, car en s'inspirant du meilleur de Scala, Groovy, Go, ... et en ciblant les meilleures VM disponibles, Kotlin part avec beaucoup d'avantages. En prenant le temps avant de sortir la v1.0, beaucoup de pièges classiques ont étés évités. Dès aujourd'hui le langage profite d'un outillage mature, tout en étant très abordable pour les développeurs. Au travers d'exemples concrets sur différentes plateformes (Android, BackEnd, FrontEnd, Natif), venez découvrir les éléments du langages qui ont su nous séduire.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-21</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-21</endDate>
        <location>Herzliya, Israel</location>
        <speaker>Haim Michael</speaker>
        <title>Life Michael</title>
        <subject>Kotlin Fundamentals [Course]</subject>
        <url>http://lifemichael.com/moodle/mod/page/view.php?id=13796</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>The course includes 90 academic hours delivered in 18 weekly meetings, that take place in class, and 180 academic hours (and beyond) that take place at home. The training material (slides, video clips, assignments, solutions and code samples) for the entire course is organized on the e-learning platform we use during the course. Each meeting includes a theoretical lecture together with practical practice (at least 30% of each meeting). The practical practice includes coding by the trainer followed by the students and coding by the students with the assistance of the trainer.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-06-18</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-06-18</endDate>
        <location>Herzliya, Israel</location>
        <speaker>Haim Michael</speaker>
        <title>Life Michael</title>
        <subject>Kotlin Fast Track [Seminar]</subject>
        <url>http://lifemichael.com/moodle/mod/page/view.php?id=13675</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Taking this seminar you will become familiar with Kotlin and be able to use it in your code when developing native applications for the Android platform and in general. This seminar will be captured on video in order to allow you going over the material when the webinar ends. Attending this webinar on-line is feasible. When doing so, the fee remains the same. This seminar will be delivered in English. When taking place in Israel it will be delivered in Hebrew. Each participant should come with his own laptop. Wifi connectivity will be available.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-15</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-15</endDate>
        <location>Chicago, USA</location>
        <speaker>Mark Ducommun</speaker>
        <title>Chicago Kotlin Users Group</title>
        <subject>Exception Handling: An Intro to Railway Oriented Programming</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Chicago-Kotlin/events/249180244/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>If you think that removing checked exceptions was the best thing Kotlin did for error handling then you are probably missing out on a big part of the language: sealed class hierarchies. Whether using the optional or either, these data types help clarify the handling of both success cases and failure cases throughout your codebase. Drop by to learn more and maybe even hack around with railway oriented programming.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-15</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-15</endDate>
        <location>Zagreb, Croatia</location>
        <speaker>Domagoj Madunić</speaker>
        <title>Java Zagreb</title>
        <subject>Migration guide to Kotlin for Spring Developers</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Java-Zagreb/events/250301474/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Quick introduction on migrating to Kotlin from Java for Spring developers. The talk will cover common pitfalls and design differences of the new environment, and is intended for Spring developers who wish to switch to Kotlin from Java, yet retain all the benefits of battle tested and powerful Spring framework.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-15</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-15</endDate>
        <location>Santa Cruz, CA</location>
        <speaker>John Kaster</speaker>
        <title>Santa Cruz Kotlin User Group</title>
        <subject>Kotlin and JRuby interop</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Santa-Cruz-Kotlin-User-Group/events/248841601/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>it</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-18</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-18</endDate>
        <location>Pisa, Italy</location>
        <speaker>Nicola Corti</speaker>
        <title>GDG Pisa</title>
        <subject>Kotlin in Action</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GDG-Pisa/events/250846388/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-19</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-19</endDate>
        <location>Kolkata, India</location>
        <speaker>Rivu Chakraborty</speaker>
        <title>GDG Kolkata</title>
        <subject>Development with Kotlin and Android</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GDG-Kolkata/events/250550266/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>es</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-19</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-19</endDate>
        <location>Alcalá de Henares, Spain</location>
        <speaker>José Antonio Dongil Sánchez</speaker>
        <title>Codenares</title>
        <subject>Kotlin = Java con súper poderes</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/codenares/events/249948011/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>pt</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-19</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-19</endDate>
        <location>Divinópolis, Brazil</location>
        <speaker>Júlio Cezar Borges</speaker>
        <title>GDG Divinópolis</title>
        <subject>Kotlin + Anko - Simplificando o que já é simples</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GDG-Divinopolis/events/250598868/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Utilização das bibliotecas Anko para aumentar a produtividade e diminuir a curva de aprendizado no desenvolvimento Android com Kotlin.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-19</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-19</endDate>
        <location>Lagos, Nigeria</location>
        <speaker>Eyitayo Alimi</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin Nigeria User Group</title>
        <subject>Kotlin Beyond Android</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Kotlin-Nigeria-User-Group/events/249868046/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Kotlin for Android -yes we are aware - but Kotlin for other projects , are we? Join us as we commence a series of events to show developers and non-developers alike, how else they could use Kotlin outside Android development.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-09</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-09</endDate>
        <location>London, UK</location>
        <speaker>Konrad Kamiński</speaker>
        <title>Devoxx UK 2018</title>
        <subject>Asynchronous programming with Kotlin coroutines</subject>
        <url>https://www.devoxx.co.uk/</url>
        <content>
            <video>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EC9-CTwrg4U&amp;utm_source=dlvr.it&amp;utm_medium=twitter</video>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Coroutines is a new feature in Kotlin 1.1. It allows for writing an asynchronous code almost just like if it was regular/synchronous. This makes coroutines a great alternative to existing approaches for writing asynchronous applications.</p>
<p>In this session, I'll show how coroutines work in Kotlin. You'll learn about new syntax and implementation details. You'll find out about the differences between coroutines-based and reactive-based solutions. You'll also see a sample Spring-based application which uses coroutines.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-23</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-23</endDate>
        <location>Detroit, MI, USA</location>
        <speaker>Todd Ginsberg</speaker>
        <title>Detroit Java User Group</title>
        <subject>Is Kotlin Right for You?</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Detroit-Java-User-Group/events/250560213/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Sure Java pays the bills for some of us, but there’s no reason why we can’t have fun developing again. Kotlin, developed by JetBrains, has been catching on lately because of its functional nature, null safety, type inference, full interoperability with Java, cross-platform support, and ease of use with Android and Spring. Is this something you and your team should considering spending time to learn?</p>
<p>In this session we will go over what Kotlin is, what problems it solves, and what makes it stand out from other JVM languages. You’ll come away with enough knowledge to decide if this is something you and your team should consider adopting.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>pt</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-27</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-27</endDate>
        <location>Cascavel,Brasil</location>
        <speaker>Ubiratan Soares</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin Night Cascavel</title>
        <subject>Kotlin DSL</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Kotlin-Meetup-Cascavel/events/249548017/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>pt</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-27</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-27</endDate>
        <location>Cascavel,Brasil</location>
        <speaker>Ivan Reffati</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin Night Cascavel</title>
        <subject>Kotlin: Do It Clean</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Kotlin-Meetup-Cascavel/events/249548017/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-18</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-18</endDate>
        <location>Indianapolis, IN, US</location>
        <speaker>Jeff Butler</speaker>
        <title>Indy.Code()</title>
        <subject>Introduction to Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://indycode.amegala.com/Sessions</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>It's time to learn Kotlin! The Spring Framework has embraced Kotlin as a first class language, and Kotlin is also becoming the language of choice for native Android development.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-15</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-15</endDate>
        <location>Greater Noida, India</location>
        <speaker>Shashank Sharma</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin NIGHT-Greater Noida</title>
        <subject>Get started with kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.facebook.com/events/1947807585534470/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>this will be first ever kotlin night for the Greater-Noida which will help developer community of Greater-Noida to get started with kotlin.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-15</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-15</endDate>
        <location>Ondo, Nigeria</location>
        <speaker>Sunkanmi Ijatuyi</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin Ondo User Group</title>
        <subject>Using Kotlin to build API</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Kotlin-Ondo-User-Group/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>To give a well detail description on how to use Kotlin (using KTOR framework)  to build API that has endpoints to post, update, delete, read for interacting with other platform. </p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-12</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-12</endDate>
        <location>Zagreb, Croatia</location>
        <speaker>Marko Božić</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin Zagreb</title>
        <subject>Improving Rx properties with Kapt</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Kotlin-Zagreb/events/248886948/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>In the first part, I’ll explain why we use Rx and which properties of Rx sequences are the ones we care about while developing mobile applications. After that, we’ll talk about how to prove that your code satisfies these properties and how Kapt can help us achieve that.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-12</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-12</endDate>
        <location>Zagreb, Croatia</location>
        <speaker>Miroslav Radanović</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin Zagreb</title>
        <subject>Kotlin - multiplatform support</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Kotlin-Zagreb/events/248886948/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>This talk will introduce you with possibilities of Kotlin multi-platform feature. Share same code base and business logic between different platforms, while managing to persist native app look and feel.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>tr</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-25</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-25</endDate>
        <location>Düzce, Turkey</location>
        <speaker>Burcu Geneci</speaker>
        <title>Women Techmakers IWD’18 Düzce</title>
        <subject>Introduction to Kotlin</subject>
        <url>http://gdgduzce.com/women-techmakers-iwd18-duzce/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Kotlin is introduced and backed from Google and Jetbrains at Google I/O 17. It will be a short quick and warming introduction section for Kotlin language. Performance and advantages of Kotlin language will be discussed.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-27</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-27</endDate>
        <location>Columbus, OH</location>
        <speaker>Michael Yotive</speaker>
        <title>Columbus Kotlin User Group</title>
        <subject>And now for something completely different - Kotlin JS</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Columbus-Kotlin-User-Group/events/248570233/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Kotlin on the Server! Kotlin on Android! Kotlin on the... browser?</p>
<p>Did you know, since version 1.1, the Kotlin compiler has offered a production-grade Kotlin-to-JavaScript transpiler? Using Kotlin/JS, we can not only use Kotlin for interacting with DOM elements, but we can also use Kotlin to communicate with server-side JavaScript such as Node.js! In this talk, we'll poke around the Kotlin transpiler and examine the javascript code that gets produced. We will go through several small projects to get a better understanding as to why you might choose Kotlin instead TypeScript or JavaScript for your application.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-27</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-27</endDate>
        <location>Austin, USA</location>
        <speaker>Barry Feigenbaum Ph.D.</speaker>
        <title>Austin Java Users Group</title>
        <subject>The Case for Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Austin-Java-Users-Group/events/249008464/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Kotlin is a new language designed to run on the JRE, on Android and over JavaScript. Join Dr. Feigenbaum as he presents a high-level introduction to the Kotlin language and shows you why you just might want to consider making it your new first language.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-28</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-28</endDate>
        <location>Columbia, MO</location>
        <speaker>Jon Schneider</speaker>
        <title>devcomo</title>
        <subject>Kotlin for Java Developers</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/devcomo/events/248705303/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>es</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-11</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-11</endDate>
        <location>Valencia, Spain</location>
        <speaker>Victor Bolinches</speaker>
        <title>Sessió Enginyeria Web, Cloud i Móbil</title>
        <subject>An Introduction to Kotlin for Android Development</subject>
        <url>https://www.uv.es/congressosdi/masterclass18/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Concise, safe, interoperable and tool-friendly regarding Java, the students will learn to use the kotlin syntax to create a native application from scratch.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>es</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-03</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-03</endDate>
        <location>La Paz, Bolivia</location>
        <speaker>Brayan Mamani Mamani</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin El Alto</title>
        <subject>Fundamentos de Kotlin: Conclusiones</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Kotlin-El-Alto/events/249062565/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>What are the scopes of using Kotlin,  Object oriented programming with Kotlin, Android with Kotlin</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-03</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-03</endDate>
        <location>Dunedin, New Zealand</location>
        <speaker>Albert Gao</speaker>
        <title>Code Craft Dunedin</title>
        <subject>Using Kotlin to share code between Android and iOS</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Code-Craft-Dunedin/events/249018033/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>tr</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-03</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-03</endDate>
        <location>Istanbul, Turkey</location>
        <speaker>Sunum Hakkında</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin Istanbul</title>
        <subject>One Way Ticket To Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Kotlin-%C4%B0stanbul/events/248641761/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Kotlin programlama dilinin kullanım kolaylıklarından ve varolan java projemizi ve java kodlarımızı nasıl daha kolay ve functional bir şekilde Kotline diline çevirebileceğimizden bahsedecek. Sunum sonunda kotlin programala dilinin birçok yeniliği hakkında bilgi sahibi olacaksınız.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-04</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-04</endDate>
        <location>San Diego, CA</location>
        <speaker>Ian Brandt</speaker>
        <title>San Diego Kotlin User Group</title>
        <subject>Dinner and a Movie - Kotlin Coroutines</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/sd-kotlin/events/249164950/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
            <p>Let's watch and discuss some KotlinConf 2017 presentations on Coroutines!</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-04</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-04</endDate>
        <location>Philadelphia, PA, USA</location>
        <speaker>Audrey Troutt</speaker>
        <title>GDG Philadelphia: Android Alliance</title>
        <subject>Kotlin Study Jam - Session 3</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GDGPhilly/events/248650148/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>it</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-04</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-04</endDate>
        <location>Turin, Italy</location>
        <speaker>Roberto Orgiu, Roberto Franchini</speaker>
        <title>GDG Torino</title>
        <subject>A Kotlin Perspective</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GDG-Torino/events/248799142/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>La portata principale sarà Kotlin, preso in esame da due prospettive molto diverse: sviluppo Mobile da una parte e Cloud dall’altra!</p>
<p>E parlando di cibo, l’evento si aprirà con un aperitivo di benvenuto, offerto da Leva Engineering, dove potrai conoscere il nostro team e i partner dell’evento.</p>
<p>Aprirà la seconda parte il talk sullo sviluppo Android, dove potrai scoprire come le nuove librerie KTX possono velocizzare lo sviluppo di un'app Android come mai prima d’ora.</p>
<p>Seguirà infine Roberto Franchini, che tratterà delle potenzialità di Kotlin per la gestione di un flusso dati continuo da Twitter con una sessione di live-coding.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-04</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-04</endDate>
        <location>Brighton, United Kingdom</location>
        <speaker>Chetan Padia</speaker>
        <title>Brighton Java</title>
        <subject>Kotlin makes Java null and void</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Brighton-Java/events/248669785/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Kotlin is a new JVM language developed by Jetbrains. In just a few years it has become a serious rival to other JVM languages including Java itself. Chetan Padia looks at why Java developers should start writing Kotlin today and what he wishes he had known before starting. The talk will provide a basic introduction to Kotlin and look in particular at its use on mobile.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>de</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-25</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-25</endDate>
        <location>Görlitz, Germany</location>
        <speaker>Tobias Blaschke</speaker>
        <title>Java User Group Görlitz</title>
        <subject>Kotlin</subject>
        <url>http://www.jug-gr.de/2018/04/25/kotlin.html</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Die Ankündigung der Unterstützung von Kotlin für die Android-Entwicklung auf der Google I/O Keynote 2017 bewirkte spontan kräftigen Applaus. Kotlin ist nur eine weitere Programmiersprache für die JVM. Warum also bewirkt die verhältnismäßig dröge Ankündigung zur Unterstützung einer JVM-Sprache solche Begeisterung? Was ist das Besondere an Kotlin gegenüber Java? Der Vortrag gibt einen ersten allgemeinen Einblick in die Sprachfeatures von Kotlin und gibt Kotlin-Neulingen die Möglichkeit sich selbst einen Eindruck über die Sprache zu verschaffen.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>de</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-10</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-10</endDate>
        <location>Braunschweig, Germany</location>
        <speaker>Jan-Lukas Else</speaker>
        <title>Braunschweiger Technology Meetup</title>
        <subject>Android Meets Kotlin - Mit Kotlin die Android-Entwicklung vereinfachen</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Braunschweiger-Technology-Meetup/events/247868951/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>A short presentation about how to use Kotlin to simplify Android development presenting the general Kotlin advantages as well as Android specific features and tools.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>es</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-05</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-05</endDate>
        <location>La Paz, Bolivia</location>
        <speaker>Brayan Mamani Mamani</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin El Alto</title>
        <subject>Fundamentos de Kotlin: Sesión 1</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Kotlin-El-Alto/events/248981657/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-05</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-05</endDate>
        <location>Limerick, Ireland</location>
        <speaker>Brian Keating</speaker>
        <title>Limerick AI - (Applications &amp; Games) Software Development</title>
        <subject>Introduction - Why Kotlin is worth considering</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/LimerickAISD/events/246487594/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>pt</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-05</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-05</endDate>
        <location>Porto Alegre, Brasilia</location>
        <speaker>Pablo Baldez</speaker>
        <title>GDG Porto Alegre</title>
        <subject>Habemus Kotlin. Mas e daí? Usando a nova linguagem oficial para Android em um app com milhões de
            downloads.
        </subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GDG-Porto-Alegre/events/249038633/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-06</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-06</endDate>
        <location>Eschborn, Germany</location>
        <speaker>Victor Oliveira</speaker>
        <title>Liferay dev.life (EMEA)</title>
        <subject>Building a truly serverless mobile app with WeDeploy and Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Liferay-dev-life-EMEA/events/249031957/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>WeDeploy helps you build from simple to complex applications. It gives you predefined services that can speed up your development process.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>es</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-06</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-06</endDate>
        <location>Lima, Peru</location>
        <speaker>Bruno Aybar</speaker>
        <title>Google Tech Lima - GTechLima</title>
        <subject>Kotlin Functions: From Zero To Hero</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GTechLima/events/249390914/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>es</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-06</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-06</endDate>
        <location>Lima, Peru</location>
        <speaker>Hansy Schmitt</speaker>
        <title>Google Tech Lima - GTechLima</title>
        <subject>KotlinJS</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GTechLima/events/249390914/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>ja</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-07</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-07</endDate>
        <location>Alexandria, Egypt</location>
        <speaker>Wessam Elsharawy, Nader Khaled</speaker>
        <title>GDG Alexandria</title>
        <subject>Kotlin Workshop</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GDG-Alexandria/events/249120224/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>ru</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-06</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-06</endDate>
        <location>Moscow, Russia</location>
        <speaker>Dmitry Zhemerov</speaker>
        <title>JPoint 2018</title>
        <subject>Идиоматичный Kotlin: от форматирования до DSL</subject>
        <url>https://jpoint.ru/talks/3hvhevcj2uwuums0umayam/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Начать пользоваться Kotlin несложно — он похож на Java, и ваш существующий опыт легко позволит вам начать программировать в стиле Java. В этом докладе вы узнаете о возможностях языка и стандартной библиотеки Kotlin, которые позволят вам выйти на следующий уровень и писать по-настоящему компактный и выразительный код. Сочетание этих возможностей позволяет строить на базе Kotlin так называемые «доменно-ориентированные языки», которые позволяют декларативно выражать сложные наборы инструкций. Мы рассмотрим несколько примеров таких языков и то, как вы сможете сами создавать их.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>ru</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-06</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-06</endDate>
        <location>Moscow, Russia</location>
        <speaker>Ivan Osipov</speaker>
        <title>JPoint 2018</title>
        <subject>Kotlin DSL: теория и практика</subject>
        <url>https://jpoint.ru/talks/50rpupwvu8yeyccm2weykg/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Разработка тестов приложения — не самое приятное занятие. Этот процесс занимает долгое время, требует большой концентрации и при этом крайне востребован. Язык Kotlin дает набор инструментов, который позволяет довольно легко построить собственный проблемно-ориентированный язык (DSL). В нашем опыте Kotlin DSL заменил билдеры и статические методы для тестирования модуля планирования ресурсов, что превратило добавление новых тестов и поддержку старых из рутины в увлекательный процесс.</p>
<p>В ходе доклада мы разберем все основные инструменты из арсенала разработчика и то, как их можно комбинировать для решения задач тестирования. Мы с вами проделаем путь от проектирования Идеального Теста до запуска максимально приближенного, чистого и понятного теста для системы планирования ресурсов на основе Kotlin.</p>
<p>Доклад будет полезен практикующим инженерам, тем, кто рассматривает Kotlin как язык для комфортного написания компактных тестов, и тем, кто хочет улучшить процесс тестирования в своем проекте.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>


    <event>
        <lang>ru</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-06</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-06</endDate>
        <location>Moscow, Russia</location>
        <speaker>Andrey Breslav</speaker>
        <title>JPoint 2018</title>
        <subject>На плечах гигантов: языки, у которых учился Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://jpoint.ru/talks/5wmp0rstnkcogqmqq02mac/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Расскажем о тех языках, из которых мы заимствовали идеи и концепции, когда разрабатывали Kotlin. В числе прочего, речь пойдет о Java, C#, Scala, Groovy, Python, Gosu и т.д. Покажем, как некоторые из этих идей изменились в нашей интерпретации. И немного расскажем о том, какие известные языки теперь учатся на нашем опыте (Swift, Java, Hack, C#).</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-24</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-24</endDate>
        <location>Bucharest, Romania</location>
        <speaker>Antonel Ernest Pazargic, Gabi Bornea</speaker>
        <title>Kotlin User Group Bucharest</title>
        <subject>Kotlin Explained Series - Functional Programming</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/kug-bucharest/events/248498109/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Kotlin its a strong type programming language which embraces both Functional and Object Oriented paradigms.
This brings the power of the two "worlds" -> functional programming in the small and object oriented programming in the large.</p>
<p>In this first part of the series we are going to see how Kotlin (and arrow) embraces the functional programming paradigm to lead to more maintainable, easy to reason, succinct yet expressive and concurrent friendly applications.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>uk</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-17</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-17</endDate>
        <location>Kiev, Ukraine</location>
        <speaker>Artem Dorosh</speaker>
        <title>OSDC</title>
        <subject>Approaching Clean Architecture in Android with Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://dou.ua/calendar/20785/?from=tw</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Світ все більше рухається в сторону wearable-девайсів, об’єм мобільного трафіка росте з нереальною швидкістю, а люди ні на хвилину не розстаються зі своїми смартфонами. В таких реаліях розробка під Android стає не просто крутою професією, а невід’ємною складовою технічного прогресу.</p>
<p>Артем Дорош розповість про те, як писати круті Android-застосунки на Kotlin. В Артема за спиною 4 роки професійної розробки під Android, тому точно буде багато цікавої інфи.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-10</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-10</endDate>
        <location>Masqat, Oman</location>
        <speaker>Isaq Almanji</speaker>
        <title>GDG Muscat</title>
        <subject>Learning about Kotlin’s great features</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/GDG_Muscat/events/249424570/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>de</lang>
        <startDate>2018-04-25</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-04-25</endDate>
        <location>Mainz,Germany</location>
        <speaker>Philipp Hauer</speaker>
        <title>JAX 2018</title>
        <subject>Kotlin in Practice</subject>
        <url>https://jax.de/core-java-jvm-languages/kotlin-in-practice/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-05-05</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-05-05</endDate>
        <location>Lahore, Pakistan</location>
        <speaker>Zahid Mahmood</speaker>
        <title>RocksTech</title>
        <subject>Know about kotlin</subject>
        <url>
            https://www.facebook.com/idnsemarang/photos/a.1777073759237576.1073741834.1764900577121561/2000514256893524/?type=3&amp;theater
        </url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>What is Kotlin , how it helps developers ,is Kotlin beter than java.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-11-19</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-11-19</endDate>
        <location>San Francisco, USA</location>
        <speaker>Kevin Galligan</speaker>
        <title>.droidconSF</title>
        <subject>Kotlin Multiplatform In Production</subject>
        <url>https://sf.droidcon.com</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Kotlin Native, with the ability to produce iOS code, was announced at KotlinConf 2017. With rapid progress on the runtime and tools, and intense community interest, several major architectural libraries have been released. KotlinConf 2018 will definitely see significant releases both, in both libraries and tools, and likely an official v1 of Kotlin Native.</p>
<p>2019 will be the year of significant application releases with a shared architectural base, powered by Kotlin multiplatform. This talk will be about the framework, how it compares (favorably) to other options, the current state of the ecosystem, and where developers eager to get involved in significant open source contributions can get started.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-11-19</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-11-19</endDate>
        <location>San Francisco, USA</location>
        <speaker>Juliano Moraes</speaker>
        <title>.droidconSF</title>
        <subject>Netflix's componentization architecture with RxJava + Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.sf.droidcon.com/sessions-1</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Recently we rewrote the Netflix's player UI using a new architecture that allows great reusability, testability and extendability.</p>
<p>This talk is about our journey from a monolithic fragment to several independent and reusable components and how it is helping us to move fast with our AB tests.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-11-19</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-11-19</endDate>
        <location>San Francisco, USA</location>
        <speaker>Aleksei Zakharov</speaker>
        <title>.droidconSF</title>
        <subject>Minimalist Dependency Injection in Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.sf.droidcon.com/sessions-1</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-11-19</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-11-19</endDate>
        <location>San Francisco, USA</location>
        <speaker>Brent Watson</speaker>
        <title>.droidconSF</title>
        <subject>Advanced Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.sf.droidcon.com/sessions-1</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>If you want to up your Kotlin game, come check out some advanced language features. Some of the things we'll cover are: delegates, covariance/contravariance, tailrec, sealed classes, kotlin's reflection API, coroutines, and more.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-11-19</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-11-19</endDate>
        <location>San Francisco, USA</location>
        <speaker>Cecilia Castillo</speaker>
        <title>.droidconSF</title>
        <subject>If your code looks like it's Kotlin &amp; quacks like it's Kotlin, then it probably is Swift.</subject>
        <url>https://www.sf.droidcon.com/sessions-1</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-11-19</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-11-19</endDate>
        <location>San Francisco, USA</location>
        <speaker>Israel Ferrer Camacho</speaker>
        <title>.droidconSF</title>
        <subject>From Effective Java to Effective Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.sf.droidcon.com/sessions-1</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-11-19</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-11-19</endDate>
        <location>San Francisco, USA</location>
        <speaker>Joaquim Verges</speaker>
        <title>.droidconSF</title>
        <subject>Quick and clean prototypes that scale with Helium: a reactive MVP framework in Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.sf.droidcon.com/sessions-1</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-11-20</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-11-20</endDate>
        <location>Copenhagen, Denmark</location>
        <speaker>Roman Elizarov</speaker>
        <title>Goto Conference</title>
        <subject>Fresh Async With Kotlin</subject>
        <url>http://gotocph.com</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Asynchronous programming is on the rise. Modern software systems are connected and constantly communicating. Programming languages are adding some form of asynchronous programming like async/await. However, Kotlin had taken a fresh approach to this problem with Kotlin Coroutines.</p>
<p>In this talk, we’ll study various approaches to asynchronous programming, their evolution, differences and similarities. We’ll see the problem with the traditional async/await approach that is based on futures/promises and how the Kotlin’s solution that is based on concepts of coroutines and continuations is giving us safer and easier programming model.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-11-23</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-11-23</endDate>
        <location>Copenhagen, Denmark</location>
        <speaker>Roman Elizarov</speaker>
        <title>Goto Conference</title>
        <subject>Asynchronous Programming with Kotlin</subject>
        <url>http://gotocph.com</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>This workshop covers asynchronous programming in Kotlin using coroutines. It starts with basics of asynchronous programming and its differences from blocking code and introduces concepts of suspending functions and coroutines. Dealing with the ecosystem of blocking code on JVM is covered in depth as well as best practices for managing cancellation of asynchronous operations. The workshop also covers more advanced topics of concurrent decomposition of work via futures, deep dive into coroutine contexts and includes an overview of Communication Sequential Process (CSP) approach and channels.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-11-20</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-11-20</endDate>
        <location>Malmö, Sweden</location>
        <speaker>Kevin Most</speaker>
        <title>Øredev</title>
        <subject>Idiomatic Interop with Kotlin</subject>
        <url>http://oredev.org/2018/sessions#sessions_DayLink-2_</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>One of Kotlin's most valuable features is its 100% Java interop</p>
<p>However, your clean Java code might not look so clean from Kotlin, and vice versa</p>
<p>We will discuss strategies to write code in either language, to be consumed in either language, that is safe, elegant, and idiomatic</p>
<p>We will also touch on Kotlin's interop story for other targets (common, JS, and native) and what you can do there</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-11-21</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-11-21</endDate>
        <location>Malmö, Sweden</location>
        <speaker>Simon Harrer</speaker>
        <title>Øredev</title>
        <subject>Domain-driven Design with Kotlin</subject>
        <url>http://oredev.org/2018/sessions#sessions_DayLink-3_</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>You will learn about domain-driven design and its tactical design.</p>
<p>You will learn about implementing a tactical design in Kotlin using also lesser known language features.</p>
<p>You will learn a little bit about the rules in dungeons and drago</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-11-23</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-11-23</endDate>
        <location>Kiev, Ukraine</location>
        <speaker>Marharyta Nedzelska</speaker>
        <title>Devoxx Ukraine 2018</title>
        <subject>Domain-driven Design with Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://dvua18.confinabox.com/speaker/marharyta_nedzelska</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Microservice architecture is now a huge trend. All big organizations with millions of users are doing microservices. This means they have lots of channels of communication between services and need to send and get much data. At some point, you can find yourself in a situation where your current approach doesn’t provide you with efficient communications, you pay more, wait for more, lose more etc. Maybe it’s time to look at gRPC… In this talk, we will cover the basics of gRPC, protocol buffers, and its usage. We will try to understand its pros and cons and where this approach could be used. We will also compare this approach with the alternatives. The most interesting about this talk is that we will have lots of practice. We will learn how to write .proto files, how to make effective communication between your microservices, and of course, write much code (in Kotlin)</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-12-01</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-12-01</endDate>
        <location>Sandton, South Africa</location>
        <speaker>Pamela Hill</speaker>
        <title>GDG DevFest South Africa</title>
        <subject>Level up in Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://devfest-southafrica.firebaseapp.com/schedule/2018-12-01?sessionId=147</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Kotlin has taken the Android world by storm since its official support in 2017. Many Android developers are coding or have at least an active interest in Kotlin. This talk aims to help Android developers level up their Kotlin skills, focussing on intermediate/expert language features such as coroutines, DSLs, and libraries/frameworks such as Koin for dependency injection, and Spek for testing.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>tr</lang>
        <startDate>2018-11-04</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-11-04</endDate>
        <location>Istanbul, Turkey</location>
        <speaker>Hadi Tok</speaker>
        <title>GDG DevFest Istanbul</title>
        <subject>RxJava ve Kotlin Coroutines, Kullanim senaryolari</subject>
        <url>https://devfest.istanbul/schedule/2018-11-04?sessionId=115</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>RxJava bir çok kullanımı olan güçlü bir araç. Asenkron işlem ve fonksiyonel programlamanın bir çok öğesini kullanıma sunuyor. Fakat Kotlin fonksiyonel programlama özelliklerini şimdiden, Asenkron işlemleri kolaylaştıran ve ucuzlaştıran Coroutine'leri 1.3 versiyonu ile sağlıyor. RxJava ve Kotlinin bu özelliklerinin karşılaştıracağım.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-11-06</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-11-06</endDate>
        <location>Toronto, Canada</location>
        <speaker>Enrique López Mañas</speaker>
        <title>AndroidTO</title>
        <subject>Kotlin/Native for Multiplatform Development</subject>
        <url>http://androidto.com/#kotlin</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Reliable multiplatform development has been the Holy Grail for Mobile Developers since its inception. Many frameworks did appear and disappear. Kotlin/Native has come strongly, and since it is still in Beta version there are some caveats about this. Is Kotlin/Native reliable for my app? Is it production-ready?</p>
<p>Come to this talk to learn what Kotlin/Native can do for you.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-11-06</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-11-06</endDate>
        <location>Toronto, Canada</location>
        <speaker>Francisco Estévez García</speaker>
        <title>AndroidTO 2018</title>
        <subject>Simple dependency management in Kotlin</subject>
        <url>http://androidto.com/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>In this talk we will discover how we can use just Kotlin features to inject dependencies through our codebase. Using this novel approach we'll introduce the concept of Type Classes, a unit of abstraction and configuration used to architect apps and libraries.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-11-16</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-11-16</endDate>
        <location>Jurmala, Latvia</location>
        <speaker>Zan Markan</speaker>
        <title>AndroidTO 2018</title>
        <subject>The State of The Kotlin Ecosystem</subject>
        <url>https://devfest2018.gdg.lv/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>In early 2018 I ran a survey of the global Kotlin ecosystem. My goal was to learn how developers use and adopt Kotlin - either in work or side projects, or just for playing around, and what are some of the most popular resources for learning it. The survey was a great success, and gained over 2000 responses in total! The results are meant to become a resource for the Kotlin community. Something we can all look at for interesting insights that will also help drive adoption of Kotlin in our teams and organisations. To give you a taster, here’s a few questions I asked in the survey: How big is Android as a proportion of all Kotlin developers Are people happy naming libraries and tooling with K What are the favourite features of the language What kind of DSLs are people building with Kotlin and for what use-cases In my talk will answer all these questions, and more. But be warned, some answers might surprise you.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-11-16</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-11-16</endDate>
        <location>Jurmala, Latvia</location>
        <speaker>Svyatoslav Scherbina</speaker>
        <title>AndroidTO 2018</title>
        <subject>Using Kotlin to share code between iOS and Android</subject>
        <url>https://devfest2018.gdg.lv/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>This talk is devoted to using Kotlin to share code between Android and iOS. It also covers Kotlin features and evolution making this possible and convenient. Kotlin Multiplatform Programming is a technology for multiplatform programming in Kotlin. It supports combining both common and platform-specific code in a single codebase with proper tooling enabled. Kotlin/Native is a technology for compiling Kotlin code to native binaries. Kotlin code has seamless interoperability with native platform (e.g. iOS) in this case. The speaker will describe how Kotlin/Native works, what is supported and what is not.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-11-16</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-11-16</endDate>
        <location>Jurmala, Latvia</location>
        <speaker>Marcin Moskała</speaker>
        <title>AndroidTO 2018</title>
        <subject>Superpowers of Property Delegation</subject>
        <url>https://devfest2018.gdg.lv/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Let's dive into possibilities that Kotlin delegation gives. Let’s discover property delegation and understand its superpowers.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>ru</lang>
        <startDate>2018-11-20</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-11-20</endDate>
        <location>St. Petersburg, Russia</location>
        <speaker>Nikita Koval</speaker>
        <title>Joker 2018</title>
        <subject>Как устроены каналы в корутинах в Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://jokerconf.com/2018/talks/2czsxh6yaqcmqc2a2asaqa/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>В отличие от классического многопоточного программирования с манипулированием разделяемой памятью, корутины общаются друг с другом при помощи каналов. Канал позволяет одной корутине отправить элемент, а другой — получить его. При этом данные операции могут быть синхронизированы, и отправитель может ждать получателя и наоборот.</p>
<p>В этом докладе мы поговорим об устройстве каналов в различных языках и библиотеках, о разработанном в Kotlin алгоритме и узнаем, кто круче: Kotlin или Go.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>ru</lang>
        <startDate>2018-11-20</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-11-20</endDate>
        <location>St. Petersburg, Russia</location>
        <speaker>Evgeny Mandrikov</speaker>
        <title>Joker 2018</title>
        <subject>Java 4..11, Kotlin, Code Coverage и их лучший друг — байткод: скандалы, интриги, расследования
        </subject>
        <url>https://jokerconf.com/2018/talks/10hiblizhceweosio0y66u/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Знаете ли вы, что внутри ваших .class-файлов? А готовы поспорить? Давайте повеселимся, исследуя конструкции байт-кода, и изучим, как различные компиляторы (Java/Kotlin) и их версии, включая недавно выпущенный javac 11, преобразуют ваш исходный код.</p>
p>Наши исследования будут основаны на деталях реализации самого популярного инструмента для анализа покрытия Java-кода тестами — JaCoCo, чья недавно выпущенная версия находит в байт-коде и отфильтровывает вспомогательные конструкции, генерируемые компиляторами, которые в противном случае требуют зачастую сложных и ненужных ухищрений, чтобы добиться полного покрытия кода.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>ru</lang>
        <startDate>2018-11-20</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-11-20</endDate>
        <location>Moscow, Russia</location>
        <speaker>Anton Keks</speaker>
        <title>Mobius 2018</title>
        <subject>Kotlin puzzlers, Vol. 2</subject>
        <url>https://mobiusconf.com/en/talks/cejpjlsjpgag2i4gaoaa0/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Kotlin is a marvelous language that makes programming on the JVM fun again. During the design phase of the language, it was said that Kotlin specifically tried to avoid some of the most famous Java Puzzlers. However, having so many advanced features, it cannot avoid introducing puzzlers of its own. This talk will present some of the more interesting nuances of syntax or language features with the help of small puzzler programs letting the audience guess their behavior. The mystery will then be revealed with an explanation in a fun way.</p>
<p>Having received an overwhelmingly good feedback from the previous version, Anton is ready with a set of completely new puzzlers to entertain you among all these really serious talks!</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>ru</lang>
        <startDate>2018-11-20</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-11-20</endDate>
        <location>Moscow, Russia</location>
        <speaker>Svyatoslav Scherbina</speaker>
        <title>Mobius 2018</title>
        <subject>Using Kotlin to share code between Android and iOS</subject>
        <url>https://mobiusconf.com/en/talks/2edqedhw7a60kikyqa6iwo/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>This talk's main topic is how you can use Kotlin to share code between Android and iOS. We will also cover Kotlin platform development trends that make this easy and possible.</p>
<p>Kotlin Multiplatform Programming technology allows you to combine common and platform-specific code in a single codebase while also supporting tooling for this kind of development model. We'll see how this looks and discuss why it should be like this and not the other way around.</p>
<p>Kotlin/Native technology allows you to compile Kotlin into native code while also giving you an option to interact seamlessly with native platform (iOS, for example). We'll discuss what, why and how does (and does not) work.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-10-25</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-10-25</endDate>
        <location>London, United Kingdom</location>
        <speaker>Marcin Koziński</speaker>
        <title>droidcon London 2018</title>
        <subject>Kotlinise your Gradle Build Scripts and Plugins</subject>
        <url>https://skillsmatter.com/conferences/10301-droidcon-london-2018#program</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Are you using Gradle to build your Android app? Are you writing Gradle plug-ins? You'll be delighted to learn you can do it in Kotlin and it'll make your life better 🙂/p>
<p>Gradle Kotlin DSL is this new thing that aims to fix some annoyances you might have with your build scripts. And if you're thinking "Wait, what's Kotlin got to do with my build scripts? Ain't that just a JSON-ish Gradle specific text file?", then don't worry. Marcin will explain that in fact no, the build script is just code (spoiler: not Java™️ Programming Language code, but close) and how Gradle Kotlin DSL makes it better./p>
<p>He'll also take a pretty detailed look at how Gradle Kotlin DSL works for Android projects. Can you use it for your app's build script right now? Does it support the extra features (and complexity) that the Android Gradle plugin adds into the mix?/p>
<p>If you're more (or also) interested in plugin development, writing them in Kotlin is not so new, but he'll quickly show how to do it anyway because it's great and you should try it!</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-10-25</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-10-25</endDate>
        <location>London, United Kingdom</location>
        <speaker>Matthew Dolan</speaker>
        <title>droidcon London 2018</title>
        <subject>Why Effective Java Still Matters to Kotlin Developers</subject>
        <url>https://skillsmatter.com/conferences/10301-droidcon-london-2018#program</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Effective Java by Joshua Bloch profoundly influenced the design of Kotlin yet by exploring a selection of "items" from the book you will see how it is still just as relevant to Kotlin developers today when we aim to write Effective Kotlin code. For example, consider how data classes implement equals, and you can see that it doesn't follow the rules suggested and as such is not always optimal.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-10-26</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-10-26</endDate>
        <location>London, United Kingdom</location>
        <speaker>Paco Estevez</speaker>
        <title>droidcon London 2018</title>
        <subject>Simple dependency management in Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://skillsmatter.com/conferences/10301-droidcon-london-2018#program</url>
        <content>
            <video>http://uk.droidcon.com/skillscasts/12907-simple-dependency-management-in-kotlin</video>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>In this talk you will discover how we can use just Kotlin features to inject dependencies through our codebase. Using this novel approach you'll learn about the concept of Type Classes, a unit of abstraction and configuration used to architect apps and libraries.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-10-26</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-10-26</endDate>
        <location>London, United Kingdom</location>
        <speaker>Kevin Galligan</speaker>
        <title>droidcon London 2018</title>
        <subject>Kotlin Multiplatform Architecture</subject>
        <url>https://skillsmatter.com/conferences/10301-droidcon-london-2018#program</url>
        <content>
            <video>https://skillsmatter.com/skillscasts/12710-kotlin-multiplatform-architecture</video>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Code sharing options for mobile have existed for years, but most tend to be relatively obscure (Rubymotion), difficult to use (C++), or limited in scope or developer interest (J2objc). Kotlin Multiplatform will emerge as an option that allows significant sharing of logic and architecture, while still allowing easy fully native integration, and have overwhelming developer community interest. This talk explores the current ecosystem, what popular libraries and tools are available, what’s coming soon, and how to get started building multiplatform for mobile.</p>
<p>To talk review people. The status of Kotlin and multiplatform will change dramatically between now and October, so while the talk will be on this topic, it’s hard to predict exactly where you’ll be by then. Kevin has spent 2 years working on a J2objc solution to sharing architecture and has switched to Kotlin. He's recently released a functional demo of SQLite and SQLDelight running on iOS and is currently working on a formal SQLite shared library, which should be published later this month.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-10-25</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-10-25</endDate>
        <location>London, United Kingdom</location>
        <speaker>Marcin Koziński</speaker>
        <title>droidcon London 2018</title>
        <subject>Kotlinise your Gradle Build Scripts and Plugins</subject>
        <url>https://skillsmatter.com/conferences/10301-droidcon-london-2018#program</url>
        <content>
            <video>https://skillsmatter.com/skillscasts/12245-kotlinise-your-gradle-build-scripts-and-plugins</video>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Are you using Gradle to build your Android app? Are you writing Gradle plug-ins? You'll be delighted to learn you can do it in Kotlin and it'll make your life better 🙂</p>
<p>Gradle Kotlin DSL is this new thing that aims to fix some annoyances you might have with your build scripts. And if you're thinking "Wait, what's Kotlin got to do with my build scripts? Ain't that just a JSON-ish Gradle specific text file?", then don't worry. Marcin will explain that in fact no, the build script is just code (spoiler: not Java™️ Programming Language code, but close) and how Gradle Kotlin DSL makes it better.</p>
<p>He'll also take a pretty detailed look at how Gradle Kotlin DSL works for Android projects. Can you use it for your app's build script right now? Does it support the extra features (and complexity) that the Android Gradle plugin adds into the mix?</p>
<p>If you're more (or also) interested in plugin development, writing them in Kotlin is not so new, but he'll quickly show how to do it anyway because it's great and you should try it!</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-10-26</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-10-26</endDate>
        <location>London, United Kingdom</location>
        <speaker>Jorge Ortiz Fuentes</speaker>
        <title>droidcon London 2018</title>
        <subject>Workshop: Let's Migrate to Gradle Kotlin DSL</subject>
        <url>https://skillsmatter.com/conferences/10301-droidcon-london-2018#program</url>
        <content>
            <video>https://skillsmatter.com/skillscasts/12187-workshop-let-s-migrate-to-gradle-kotlin-dsl</video>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Gradle is an awesome and very powerful build tool. It is key to tune your build and even more relevant to achieve the promised karma of continuous integration. However, one of its biggest "shortcomings" is that in order to extract any drop of power juice, you need to know and use Groovy. Nothing against Groovy, but it is just another language and, very likely, one that you don't use very often. But worry no more! Now you can use the same language that you enjoy and use it when you write the code of your apps: Kotlin. During this workshop Jorge will start with a walk through some of the most relevant features of gradle. Then you will learn how to transform the gradle configuration of a project to use Kotlin DSL. You will finish by extending that configuration with a new functionality taking advantage of writing it in Kotlin. Join Jorge to kotlinize your gradle!</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-10-26</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-10-26</endDate>
        <location>London, United Kingdom</location>
        <speaker>Hadi Hariri</speaker>
        <title>droidcon London 2018</title>
        <subject>Workshop: Creating DSLs in Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://skillsmatter.com/conferences/10301-droidcon-london-2018#program</url>
        <content>
            <video>https://skillsmatter.com/skillscasts/12203-workshop-creating-dsls-in-kotlin</video>
        </content>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>One of Kotlin's powers is the ability to easily create Domain Specific Languages which can be used in your application. In this workshop you'll learn the basics of Kotlin functions and see how you can combine a series of features to create DSLs that can be used to represent a variety of things in your apps, ranging from configuration to domain logic.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-11-06</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-11-06</endDate>
        <location>Dublin, Ireland</location>
        <speaker>Daniel González Reina</speaker>
        <title>Dublin Kotlin User Group</title>
        <subject>Create a Kotlin-React App</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/Dublin-Kotlin-User-Group/events/256027670/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>In this meetup we'll learn how to create a web app using the Kotlin wrappers for React. We'll see how to take advantage of Kotlin features to write expressive code that will compile to a React application.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-11-05</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-11-05</endDate>
        <location>Oslo, Norway</location>
        <speaker>Marie Katrine Ekeberg</speaker>
        <title>Oslo Kotlin Meetup</title>
        <subject>Testing in Kotlin and YOU</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/meetup-group-nWeRbyMu/events/255357691/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>What options do you have for testing your code in Kotlin? Some people will probably just jump straight to JUnit as a testing framework, but did you know you that Spek offers an alternative approach with a domain specific language (DSL) for tests? Your choice of tools doesn't stop here. You have alternative assertion libraries, mocking frameworks and more that are different from what you may be used to in Java. The builder pattern is also even simpler in Kotlin, which make creating test data builders work like a charm. We will look at these topics and more! With examples ranging from small utility classes to integration tests with Spring.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-11-07</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-11-07</endDate>
        <location>New York, NY</location>
        <speaker>Javier Moreno Aleman, Tammy Tyberg</speaker>
        <title>New York Kotlin Meetup</title>
        <subject>NYC Subway Sign with Kotlin and Raspberry Pi</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/New-York-Kotlin-Meetup/events/255636916/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>A few months ago we were looking through a gift guide and saw one of those nice-looking, real-time Subway signs that you put on a coffee table or a bookshelf. We decided to get one, then saw the price (+$300) and thought, "Wait a minute, we're pretty sure we can just build this for less money." So after grabbing one of the many Raspberry Pis lying around the office, and with Kotlin as the weapon of choice, we embarked on a new project: Your own personal subway sign for (way) under $300.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

    <event>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <startDate>2018-11-07</startDate>
        <endDate>2018-11-07</endDate>
        <location>New York, NY</location>
        <speaker>Ryan Cooke</speaker>
        <title>New York Kotlin Meetup</title>
        <subject>Building Backend Microservices in Kotlin</subject>
        <url>https://www.meetup.com/New-York-Kotlin-Meetup/events/255636916/</url>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
<p>Ryan will describe how Kotlin has gone from a hackathon experiment to the language of choice for backend service development at N26. He will present thoughtful strategies on how to build adoption based on learnings from false-starts introducing other languages to the stack. And with a bottoms-up approach, Kotlin eventually advanced into his firm's Android applications. N26 is now an active member in the Kotlin community in Europe and is focused on applying emerging features such as coroutines to their event driven systems.</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </event>

</events>